<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><parsererror xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="display: block; white-space: pre; border: 2px solid #c77; padding: 0 1em 0 1em; margin: 1em; background-color: #fdd; color: black"><h3>This page contains the following errors:</h3><div style="font-family:monospace;font-size:12px">error on line 451 at column 330: Invalid bytes in character encoding
</div><h3>Below is a rendering of the page up to the first error.</h3></parsererror><channel><title><![CDATA[kellianna]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>kellianna</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:29:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:29:24 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[welcome to the garden]]></title><description><![CDATA[I have had some sort of web presence/blog since about 1998. I made my own websites at first, journaled on various forums, had a LiveJournal, many Wordpress blogs, and have used various social medias as a type of diary. None of these ways of capturing my thoughts for public consumption quite fit the bill of how I wanted to express myself online. While I really enjoyed the community feel of forums and social media, there was always a pressure to respond and read everyone else before posting my own words. Having a blog felt too formal. Like everything had to be just right before I could put it out to the world. Polished, with the right photo, tags, categories, date created. After hitting "post" it was "out there," never to be touched or updated again. I'm a bit obsessive when it comes to these things and once the thing was out there with a published date, I would feel like I couldn't go back to it and change it. Where would it fit? With the old date or a new one?I have been using <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://obsidian.md" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://obsidian.md" target="_self">Obsidian</a> for note taking for quite awhile now, and enjoy the flexibility of undated, living, evolving notes and writings. When books had to written out by hand by monks, when pamphlets had to be printed at the printing press, when the only way to look up a fact was in the encyclopedia, perhaps it made sense to think of things as needing to be polished and finished before the expense was put forward to make a hard copy of a story, fact, or essay. But, we live in the age of digital ink, for the lay person who is keeping a blog or finding a way to publish their ideas, there is no reason for a polished final product.<br>As I have become jaded on the idea of keeping a formal blog, I still want to have an informal online presence. As I went down the rabbit hole of options, I came across the idea of a "<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://maggieappleton.com/garden-history/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://maggieappleton.com/garden-history/" target="_self">digital garden</a>." A place to <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://notes.nicolevanderhoeven.com/Learning+in+public" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://notes.nicolevanderhoeven.com/Learning+in+public" target="_self">learn in public</a>, explore half formed ideas, and link one thought to another through building a "<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.ssp.sh/brain/second-brain" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.ssp.sh/brain/second-brain" target="_self">second brain</a>."<br>I have been using <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://obsidian.md" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://obsidian.md" target="_self">Obsidian</a> for note taking for about a year and it was the idea of linking notes and keeping "<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://notes.andymatuschak.org/Evergreen_notes?stackedNotes=zKGjQtsTKgscAoq271ZzKqw" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://notes.andymatuschak.org/Evergreen_notes?stackedNotes=zKGjQtsTKgscAoq271ZzKqw" target="_self">evergreen</a>" notes that lead me to start a garden of my own.A reverse chronologically organized space with set dates implying that these things were finished, never to be returned to and updated, wasn't working for my curiosity driven, ever changing brain. Feeling the need to have every thought fleshed out and finished before sharing made me just not write at all. Feeling like the space needed to be polished in a perfect SEO driven format with perfectly aesthetic and glossy photos wasn't my style either. I enjoyed playing. Playing with graphics and fonts and layouts, but that took away from the actual writing. I also didn't want to be a "content creator." I want to be a real person putting real thoughts on a page to connect with other real people out there.Welcome to the garden! I hope you fall down a few rabbit holes and find your wonderland ❣]]></description><link>welcome-to-the-garden.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">welcome to the garden.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:07:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01 Art Journal Ideas]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Doodles&nbsp;
Song lyrics
Geometric shapes
Quotes
Make little square swatches of different colors, textures, mediums and add them to a page or use them in collages
Text/typography (more writing and words)
monochromatic
Constellations&nbsp;
Watercolor circles
Poetry
Use my own photos in collage kraft paper
inks and oxides
gesso
tea bags
fabric
<img src="media/art/art-journal/geo_doodle.jpeg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/flower_doodle.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/circle_doodle.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/leaf_photo.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/daydreams.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/stand_up.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/leaf_doodle.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/dragonfly.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/20231230.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/2023_0326.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/20230319.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/20230220.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self"><img src="media/art/art-journal/20220609.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;" target="_self">]]></description><link>01-seeds/01-art-journal-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/01 Art Journal Ideas.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:06:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[leaf_doodle]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/art/art-journal/leaf_doodle.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/art/art-journal/leaf_doodle.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/art/art journal/leaf_doodle.JPG</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:02:56 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[geo_doodle]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/art/art-journal/geo_doodle.jpeg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/art/art-journal/geo_doodle.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/art/art journal/geo_doodle.jpeg</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:00:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[07 Journaling Ideas]]></title><description><![CDATA[What am I hungry for?What do I long for?What do I crave?What do I desire?Seek and face our truths. Listen to our souls. Let live what must live. Let die what must die. Develop intuition to know what we need and desire. Be brave enough to head that call.<a data-href="Shadow Work Journal Prompts for exploring the Female Shadow" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Shadow Work Journal Prompts for exploring the Female Shadow</a>In what ways do I deny or suppress my own needs, desires, or emotions to maintain peace or seek validation?Are there any female role models, past or present, that I feel negatively about-why is this?What are some societal messages that I have internalized about what it means to be a woman? How do these messages affect my sense of self and identity?What are some ways that I may have internalized misogyny or sexism? How can I challenge and reframe these beliefs to support my own empowerment and the empowerment of other women?What are some ways that I may have suppressed or denied my own feminine energy or power? How can I reclaim and integrate this?How have I internalized shame or guilt around my sexuality? How can I release these feelings and embrace my sexuality as natural and healthy aspect of my being?Have I internalized the belief that I must always be nurturing and selfless, at the expense of my own needs and desires? How can I learn to prioritize my own needs and desires (while still being compassionate and nurturing toward others)?How do I conform to societal beauty standards? Does this feel authentic? If not, how can I embrace my own unique beauty and reject unrealistic beauty standards?Thinking about a time I was polite and accommodating in a situation where I felt uncomfortable or unsafe - how could I have set healthy boundaries, and asserted my own needs?How have I internalized the belief that I must always be competitive and aggressive in order to succeed? How can I embrace my own unique strengths and collaborate with others in a way that supports mutual success?What are some ways that I can celebrate and honor my own femininity and the femininity of other women while rejecting harmful stereotypes and societal expectations?Thinking about a time I felt jealous around another woman, what triggered this?Reflecting on my relationship with my mother or other feminine figures, identify any areas of pain, resentment, or confusion.]]></description><link>01-seeds/07-journaling-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/07 Journaling Ideas.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:47:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[06 Poetry Lines and Ideas]]></title><description><![CDATA[ &nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.cnn.com/2013/02/03/world/europe/richard-iii-search-announcement/index.html" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.cnn.com/2013/02/03/world/europe/richard-iii-search-announcement/index.html" target="_self">the remains of King Richard III, found under a parking lot</a> the way rain drips from autumn I’ve left secrets for you, hanging in the fog why don’t you come closer and I’ll tell you more butterfly wings into dragon’s breath barefoot days with the flowers calling the colors home it's not that midnight suddenly holds peace in it's empty hands Pour me a few fingers of 80 truth the season is the reason for the trauma (I had a dream and this was a line in a song in the dream. I think it would make the perfect emo Christmas song lol) we all stay up too late , we all whisper I’m sorry to the night you never listen to the lyrics, only hear the tune a smile sits snug in the hollow of a collarbone she folds herself into herself into herself into thirds and fourths when time hovers like glass shards before the blood hummingbird heart Devil's advocate on my shoulder ‘til then I’ll keep company with the rain. I think I owe some money to September for some past due I no longer remember strip mall church What if I die
And there's no one to write a poem
To the fact that I lived
No one to eulogize the
way my laugh made them smile
No one to remember that
I always needed a book to read
and a backup book just in case
That I enjoyed a glass of plum wine
At the restaurant with the koi fish
And the tall thin sushi master everything was quiet in the loudest possible way Those are the times that haunt me
The times I was oblivious to the
Universe whispering, "not today." Do people still write their names in the front of books Learning to hold delicate things Poetry was born from the saliva of the gods In between coffee drip
And radio static the rain names me melancholy
my dreams name me blue
the crushed robin's egg
under the tree, a reminder
of one less song blowing
through another summer
without you Sinkhole with a forest inside love no longer asks to sit with me quietly
under apple trees in June. No longer asks me to carve names into old wood. Half light firefly Does she feel more soft
When the moon is a curve of a hip bone
Rather than a round belly There is nothing but the hand
On her knee
Under the stain of a red stop light What life consumed by war
reduced to smoke
reduced to Hello my name is
resting upon every chest
as though we are labeled
by what we can't control
as if we are defined by
the places we have been led Psychic antique shop Linger at the door as we say goodbye Let me tell you where I've been... I lived at the top of the world Here we all weep significant figures thistle and bone I am a summer birthday/a June wildflower Poem about dentist
How are you today
tell me if you feel any pain I had a dream that
I couldn't throw you a party
because there were too many guns
and clutter from too much consumption. This morning I spoke to a random god
told her why I could not kneel
explained to her why narcisissum
is in the DSM - V Everyone who came
Became everyone who left
Until no one remained
Who remembered my name
And the sky spanned on
And the the sea - The sea is a meticulous mandolin. the moon - The moon is a prehistoric lemon drop. death - Death is a flaccid mannequin. NASA, describing it in the most melancholy way possible, says, “Mostly, a deep silence prevails.” NASA on the sounds recorded by the Mars river My worth has absolutely
nothing to do with anyone else.
With their opinions of me,
their ideas about life,
the way they do things,
their opinions about how I do things,
their beliefs about who I am,
their opinions about what I should be doing, about what is right and wrong. My worth has absolutely nothing
to do with any of that.
It doesn't concern me. He was an old man
he was a young man
he was the man who wasn't there Capitalism will not pay for wisdom
age is a deficit of profit
the prophet can not be compensated when time hangs like
glass shards after the break
is there enough time
for a poem to form or
only for a dream to die
by word or surrender
we add pieces of ourselves the city doesn't know there is silence waiting butterfly ghost wings for this we make ourselves bleed pour me a few fingers of 80 truth butterflies drink the tears of turtles pick out a tune on a possibility heartwood blood queen a field of cosmos walk in cemeteries leaving notes of "I'll see you soon" five buttons are all that remain you left bruises
and I said I was sorry
for the way I stung
your palm. Two Skateboards
side by side
Two hearts
holding hands
Don’t let me fall I have my words to
string together,
my thoughts to sort.
Pencils to take into the woods,
logs to sit upon,
and poems to pull from the wind. I am a believer in the fact that things don't have to be overly sweet to kill you Does she let you tie her in knots He could always claim truthfully that there had never been blood on his own hands It's in these spaces where I am selfish Waiting Wednesdays She built a pedestal from
the hard marble of self loathing,
set him upon it and cried
when he shattered it with absent
fists and ghosted good byes. Do you talk to yourself sometimes? that little fat prehistoric statue sun spots 5 things (see, smell, hear, touch, taste) Fill a tent with the dead I walked on crushed flower petals/And tried to forget your name my fantasies wield knives Boys on bikes waving at trains Dreaming of the northern lights Gas station in lomira Things shaped like hearts
Leaves
Rocks
How this would represent love the punks were poets first to edge the black skirt of night composed me into measures,
and somehow echoed in
every heavy downbeat exactly
the sound of my heart beat It’s a tidal pull, this longing for open water.
but the ocean will wait.
She’s patient and understands
your desire for the taste of salty skin. a deep blackbird night.
When a bit of lightning is no
replacement for the mercy
of a white dove daybreak.
There are questions I save for the darkness,
but the darkness never replies.
It only sits silently on my chest
and steals my breath. this strange emptiness
feels like the last day of summer
like the first day of school
when 15 was old I love you and goodbye both
come at the end of something. In the days before our stomachs
became full of worry stones -
life tumbled smooth, but
not without imperfection.
wool gathered memory
lavender laughter
sage advice
we all stay up too late
we all whisper I’m sorry to the night
please don't read what the night reveals
a thin soul so see through&nbsp;that you can see through
I’m tripping spring snowmelt
Appropriating joy
I am from sea foam sea shells/mother of pearl inlay
Incised meanders
Ephemeral streams
Women gave birth to all the men who hate us. -- A woman gave birth to every woman hating man. They are born of her and that fact makes them forever try to control the givers of life that they can never become.
I had spent so long drenched
in condescension that my skin
was coated in bubbles of tension
like raindrops on pink petals
waiting to escape in rivulets Square of Roses (Paris) For the Plot Hope Pandora's box/Hope is just another cruelty Unleashed when light is reflected into your eyes/I see colors human capital value second collection of story poems
political poems
seasons
poems of a failed marriage
]]></description><link>01-seeds/06-poetry-lines-and-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/06 Poetry Lines and Ideas.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:46:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[05 Fiction Ideas]]></title><description><![CDATA[ Sometimes I silently beg for people to show me my worth -
I think I must have been a bad person in another life. A villain in another incarnation. I must have taken all the praise for myself and never uttered a kind word. I must have neglected my children, pushed away love, and sneered at friendship. I must have held kindness like a precious stone, gripped in clenched hands, all for myself and not for sharing. I must have left so many people out in the cold - unseen, unheard, and uncared for. I think I must have been a very bad person in another life.
Because no matter how much I give in this one, I am destined to remain on the outside. An empty cup. A lonely night. A restless ghost. Unseen, unheard, and uncared for.
Kindness extended. Always. Hype given. Always. Cup filled. Always. { even as I am drained } fictionalized journaling people in heaven watching themselves be slowly forgotten on Earth female hero in midlife - everyone deserves to see themselves as the hero. ]]></description><link>01-seeds/05-fiction-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/05 Fiction Ideas.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:46:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[04 Essay Ideas]]></title><description><![CDATA[
write little imagery heavy vignettes like this:
<img alt="vignette.png" src="media/vignette.png" target="_self">
Who are we writing for
Are we writing with that voice in our heads telling us it's terrible
How you come back from a long break
How doing everything the same way, following rules and “how-tos” is turning art and thinking into one voice
Holding on to old words/writing/ideas
Proper poetic form
Letting go of grudges/conflict/people who you don't like or don't like you
Maybe it's just not for me
What we're missing out on with caller ID and never getting wrong numbers. How machines not only take jobs, but get in the way of shared humanity.
where in your body do you keep your joy
write a poem or scene that takes place at night without ever mentioning that it is night. “Every sentence should contain some twilight or night… The peculiar dusky serenity of the sentences must not allow the reader to forget that it is evening or night without my saying that it is dark.” - Thoreau
spinning plates, leave them broken, buy new pretty plates, just sit down, just eat, stop spinning
What do I look for in a friendship?
Write about UFOs star wars x files. Alien abduction books of the 80s
intimacy&nbsp; over sex
We need to remember what it was to live without so much technology
Aging "past prime" society is at fault for how women approach aging
turtles are born in the dirt and seek water they have never seen nor felt (Thoreau)
How do I feel about the rules/laws of society and how we are punished for things we never got to decide are a crime?
How labeling a kind an underachiever simply on their performance in school may set them up for a lifetime of not pursuing the things they are passionate about.
essay on the muse. research muses and write about my own experience.
the sounds of words - how they feel in your mouth, how they are formed by the lips, what emotions they elicit
capitalism/ hermits aren’t good for the economy
a letter to the future
we don’t always need to take sides/have opinions
What would life look like if for the first time in your life you saw the domestic work as valuable, worthy, and necessary? Do you need to be a cog in the capitalistic machine?
what you're looking for is in the fediverse
problems with seeking "authenticity"
writing workshop thoughts
creating for joy instead of public consumption (with little pics of the things I'm creating? )
to study something deeply
don't let society erase the trauma women have faced historically Write a letter to your future self. Use this as a moment to reflect, but also write down some of your hopes and dreams. You can just use this as a journal prompt, or you can actually send it to your future self with [FutureMe]
<br><a class="auto-card-link-card is-unresolved" href="https://www.futureme.org" target="_self"><div class="auto-card-link-main"><div class="auto-card-link-title"></div><div class="auto-card-link-description"></div><div class="auto-card-link-host"><span></span></div></div></a>FutureMe: Write a Letter to your Future SelfWrite a letter to the future and read the public (but anonymous) letters from others. FutureMe has been delivering letters to the future for millions of people since 2002.<img class="auto-card-link-favicon is-unresolved" src="https://www.futureme.org/apple-touch-icon.png" target="_self">www.futureme.org<img class="auto-card-link-thumbnail is-unresolved" src="http://www.futureme.org/images/og1.png" draggable="false" target="_self">.]]></description><link>01-seeds/04-essay-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/04 Essay Ideas.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:46:06 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/vignette.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/vignette.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[03 Photography Collection Ideas]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Cities
Carnivals
Light and shadow
Colors
Butterflies
Windows
Rolling Stone music store 4/3/22]]></description><link>01-seeds/03-photography-collection-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/03 Photography Collection Ideas.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:45:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02 Collage Ideas]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="20230525_everything_dies.JPG" src="media/art/20230525_everything_dies.jpg" target="_self">
Make collages with found things from around the Internet. Tweets, pics, memes, etc
collage backgrounds for my tiny thoughts Collage of things on the golden record Space travel
Voyager
Seti
Aliens make my own calendar of collage
goddess collage
sew on collages
]]></description><link>01-seeds/02-collage-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/02 Collage Ideas.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:45:35 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/art/20230525_everything_dies.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/art/20230525_everything_dies.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[00 Seeds]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a data-href="01 Art Journal Ideas" href="01-seeds/01-art-journal-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">01 Art Journal Ideas</a><br>
<a data-href="02 Collage Ideas" href="01-seeds/02-collage-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">02 Collage Ideas</a><br>
<a data-href="03 Photography Collection Ideas" href="01-seeds/03-photography-collection-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">03 Photography Collection Ideas</a><br>
<a data-href="04 Essay Ideas" href="01-seeds/04-essay-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">04 Essay Ideas</a><br>
<a data-href="05 Fiction Ideas" href="01-seeds/05-fiction-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">05 Fiction Ideas</a><br>
<a data-href="06 Poetry Lines and Ideas" href="01-seeds/06-poetry-lines-and-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">06 Poetry Lines and Ideas</a><br>
<a data-href="07 Journaling Ideas" href="01-seeds/07-journaling-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">07 Journaling Ideas</a><br>
<a data-href="08 Creative Ideas" href="01-seeds/08-creative-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">08 Creative Ideas</a><br>
<a data-href="09 Blog &amp; Online Ideas" href="01-seeds/09-blog-&amp;-online-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">09 Blog &amp; Online Ideas</a><br>
<a data-href="09.5 Digital Garden Ideas" href="01-seeds/09.5-digital-garden-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">09.5 Digital Garden Ideas</a>
add photos to notes
add more finished poems
add journal entries
make it all pretty
]]></description><link>01-seeds/00-seeds.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/00 Seeds.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:44:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02 Seedlings]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a data-href="Unfinished Essay ~ Writing Thoughts" href="02-seedlings/unfinished-essay-~-writing-thoughts.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Unfinished Essay ~ Writing Thoughts</a><br>
<a data-href="Unfinished Poem ~ Contemplations" href="02-seedlings/unfinished-poem-~-contemplations.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Unfinished Poem ~ Contemplations</a><br>
<a data-href="Unfinished Poem ~ Simulation" href="02-seedlings/unfinished-poem-~-simulation.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Unfinished Poem ~ Simulation</a><br>
<a data-href="Unfinished Poem ~ Unfinished" href="02-seedlings/unfinished-poem-~-unfinished.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Unfinished Poem ~ Unfinished</a>]]></description><link>02-seedlings/02-seedlings.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">02 Seedlings/02 Seedlings.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:44:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="kellianna.png" src="media/kellianna.png" target="_self">Welcome to my garden! I hope you find a few rabbit holes to fall into while you're here ❣<br><img alt="Drawing.jpg" src="media/drawing.jpg" target="_self"><br>This is the word playground that a blog could never be. Here I plan to play with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="09.5 Digital Garden Ideas" data-href="09.5 Digital Garden Ideas" href="01-seeds/09.5-digital-garden-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">different ideas</a> (another thing that is discouraged in the world of blogging where every blogger must have a niche and only that one thing), publish things I'm curious about and not worry if everything is polished.<br>There are many <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/KasperZutterman/Second-Brain" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/KasperZutterman/Second-Brain" target="_self">other digital gardens or second brains</a> out there to explore and many tools for building them.<br>I have built this garden by publishing my Obsidian notes with the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://docs.obsidianweb.net" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://docs.obsidianweb.net" target="_self">Webpage HTML export plugin</a> and hosting it on Github pages.Right now the garden contains a few different stages of growth:<br><a data-href="00 Kelli Anna" href="00-kelli-anna/00-kelli-anna.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">00 Kelli Anna</a>These are just random notes, lists, and things about me. A place to get to know me, a song of myself.<br><a data-href="00 Seeds" href="01-seeds/00-seeds.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">00 Seeds</a>These are just ideas for future use. Ideas for creative pursuits, writings, this garden, the future<br><a data-href="02 Seedlings" href="02-seedlings/02-seedlings.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">02 Seedlings</a>These are unfinished beginnings of writings and other pursuits. Half baked ideas, things to return to when the time is right.<br><a data-href="03 flowers" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">03 flowers</a>Here is where the more polished, "finished" work resides. Maybe these will still be edited in the future, but for the most part they have reached the last stage of growth and are at their most beautiful.<br><a data-href="04 rabbit holes" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">04 rabbit holes</a>Topics I have fallen into and lost myself in for awhile. Nothing complete, nothing publishable, just learning for fun and mostly for myself. Learning should be a life long endeavor of rabbit holes and curiosities.Who knows what will grow here in the future ❣]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:44:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/kellianna.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/kellianna.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[00.1 The Writer]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="kellianna.png" src="media/kellianna.png" target="_self"><br><img alt="bio_pic.jpg" src="media/bio_pic.jpg" target="_self">Because my head is always full of words and I need to lay them down somewhere. I am a poet. A lifelong reader. A lazy Buddhist. A music lover. A mom. An introvert. I am someone who remains curious, overthinks, and talks too much. That’s what this place is for. A place to talk about all of the things that astonish and puzzle me. Mostly you will find poetry, short stories, essays about life, photos, and collage (paper and digital). I’m glad you’re here!<br><img alt="20231006_eclipse_of_epiphanies.jpg" src="media/art/20231006_eclipse_of_epiphanies.jpg" target="_self">I tell poetic stories that examine the connection between nature and human nature. Stories of love, rebirth, and longing. Stories of secrets hidden away in seashells and cottages of madness. Not content to limit myself, I ramble through themes and styles with the quiet voice of a conversation at midnight. I hope my poems of solitude can give you a place to rest, away from the noise and chaos of the world.<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://bsky.app/profile/kellianna.bsky.social" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://bsky.app/profile/kellianna.bsky.social" target="_self">Bluesky</a>]]></description><link>00-kelli-anna/00.1-the-writer.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">00 Kelli Anna/00.1 The Writer.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:08:41 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/kellianna.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/kellianna.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[kellianna]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/kellianna.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/kellianna.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/kellianna.png</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:08:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/kellianna.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/kellianna.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[00 Kelli Anna]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a data-href="00.1 The Writer" href="00-kelli-anna/00.1-the-writer.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">00.1 The Writer</a><br>
<a data-href="Concerts" href="00-kelli-anna/concerts.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Concerts</a><br>
<a data-href="Five Words" href="00-kelli-anna/five-words.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Five Words</a><br>
<a data-href="I Love" href="00-kelli-anna/i-love.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">I Love</a><br>
<a data-href="What Feeds Me" href="00-kelli-anna/what-feeds-me.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">What Feeds Me</a><br>
<a data-href="Women I Admire" href="00-kelli-anna/women-i-admire.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Women I Admire</a>]]></description><link>00-kelli-anna/00-kelli-anna.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">00 Kelli Anna/00 Kelli Anna.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:59:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tiny Musings]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="musings.png" src="media/musings.png" target="_self">
📌 every day in this country there is another wound on our hearts
undated I have never done any drug harder than alcohol, but I'm telling ya, when I'm an old woman I'm going to smoke a little weed and just not give a shit what other people are doing with their own damn lives.
undated (sometime in 2024?) Don't let men steal your time from creating and writing and being and rising and reaching every bit of potential you have. Goddamn, I am so fucking intelligent. I am so fucking capable. Why did I give away my power so easily? (Thoughts while reading The Bell Jar)
October 10, 2024 I drink coffee like it would kill me to remember your promises.
2024 Genocide, war, equality, rights - these things get labeled "political" when they are literally the things that impact the very life of other people or ourselves. Politics is what decides if we live freely or under fascism. Whether we have health care or not. It decides if minorities are protected or lynched. Whether bombs are dropped on children or if we agree that all life is valuable. "Politics" is our voice against evil. Every human, no matter their profession or passion, has a right to that voice and should be free to use it as loudly as they are called to do.
December 30, 2023 What if all the humans left the internet, except for bill paying and personal things? What if we let the AI generated content and all of the ads get likes and traffic from the porn bots. Let the algorithms feed themselves on machine made content only consumed by other machines? Would the internet continue on while humans read real books by real people and talked to each other again? We are headed to a place where AI is going to get so good at content creation and deepfakes that we are at risk of getting sucked into an attention dominating black hole, but where right now it's human made content pulling us in, soon it will all be machine made to cater to our very specific tastes. Machines entertaining us with machine made content while ads scroll by. Who are the people that really want that future?? The ones set to make the most money from it. At any cost.
December 29, 2023 The Secret to Life:
pay attention
love what you love
share what you love
create something
share that
repeat enthusiastically
July 17, 2023 We are the latest of a people once new, who've forgotten most of what we once knew.
&gt; July 16, 2023 Maybe, for whatever reason, unknown to you now, you were born a writer. You were born to string words together. And maybe, for some unknown reason, you are supposed to string those words together in obscurity. It’s your birthright. It has always felt like your birthright. Accept it. Hold it as you would any fragile gift, and use it without fear.
Undated I want to lighten the world, to erase the creeping darkness. I want to create a space of beauty. A space that promotes what I love, rather than highlights what I hate. If we focused solely on what feeds our souls, could we not rid the world of what eats at them?
February 28, 2021 Names for my imaginary band:
pop: The Fuzzy Peppermints
indie: Rustic Church
punk: Graphic Blandishment
all girl pop punk: Yeah Nadia Can a society that measures time by wars achieve peace?
April 1, 2017 Paying the bill at dinner last night: Husband: Do you have any ones?
Me: Go fish. February 18, 2017 If I were a number, I’d be a non-terminating decimal.
January 30, 2017 Everyone deserves someone who looks at them the way Barack Obama looks at Michelle!
January 10, 2017 Go outside spontaneously when it’s freezing and you will become a whim-sicle.
December 12, 2016 Story of my life - Instead of shining brightly, I dim my glow for the approval of mediocre lovers.
November 29, 2016 My mind can't think in poetry when the pockets of silence are shallow.
September 6, 2016 Tiny sunburn on my legs makes me think I like the moonlight so much more
August 2, 2016 Dog, plane, lawnmower, car, garbage truck, ambulance - where is the silence?
June 30, 2016 Doesn’t saying “color scheme” make it seem like the colors are all plotting a scam of some kind?
June 15, 2016
Undated:
I think it says a lot about how my New Year's resolutions are going that I'm just thinking of waiting until tomorrow and turning them into Lunar New Year's resolutions. Let a little more life into your days, so that when you are at the end of that life, you may draw upon the well of experience and drink from memory. You have the right to keep your secrets. To secretly dream, to secretly love, to secretly hate. They, and your body, are the only things you own outright. I feel like the older I get the more I want to live and speak authentically. I don't want to censor myself or be someone I'm not anymore. If a cat eats a moth, is it like when we eat a powdered donut? If only I could pursue my current goals with the tenacity of 12 year old me calling the radio station over and over for a solid week trying to win Huey Lewis and the News tickets. I am the only person on a planet of almost 8 billion who just saw a chipmunk taking a bath on my back patio. For all the terrible things happening all at once, there are also so many small astonishments out there if only we take the time to really look. Do not let age put out your fire. Do not silence yourself. Do not become cold. Do not become hard. Stay soft, stay curious, stay playful. Become fierce with the passing years. The world is full of people who have no idea how technology works. Who have no idea how to research basic information. They are electing other people like them who have no idea how anything works. And the rest of us are being held hostage by their ignorance and thirst for power. It's terrifying. Social Media has created a world where we strive to be right instead of kind. We share with strangers things we are too afraid to share with friends. We’re living in a sandcastle, pretending the tide will never come. It helps to remember that no one else knows what the fuck they are doing either. Mirror, mirror on the wall - you’re so focused on looks, you judgmental jerk. Society keeps you caged with the illusion of freedom. I feel like I'm at the age where I need to start asking myself just what kind of old lady I want to be. Have you ever been nurtured?
Really.
Have you? Reconnecting with people you haven't talked to since high school is like the awkward reunion episode of a long cancelled TV show. Most things exist between the extremes. What could be waiting for you to arrive? I wonder if clouds ever look down on us and say "Hey, look! That one is shaped like
an idiot." I sat for an hour in a quiet house of bird song and wind, mom mode off. Reading of injustice and the way hearts and minds reroute and heal from destruction. Outraged at the lack of empathic response in humans who house a brain wired for connection.
]]></description><link>03-flowers/tiny-musings.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/Tiny Musings.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:56:28 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/musings.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/musings.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Passing Thoughts]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="thoughts.png" src="media/thoughts.png" target="_self">
(spring) Spring fell in three days of relentless rain. Soaking the first sprouts and turning yards to fresh mud. While we waited for the leaves, the birds filled the trees instead, with long awaited song. Soon the colors will wake from their long sleep, and we will believe that hope is what made it all bloom once more. (crone) I had a revelation last night about how I've gone through life never feeling good enough because I have based my worth on whether or not I'd be seen as attractive to a man. Last night I was like, fuck this. I want to be a wise old crone with waves of grey hair and mala beads wrapped around the skin of my crepe paper arms. I want to welcome people to come sit and talk and be comforted. To perhaps spill some wise words. I never again want to give a fuck if someone finds me attractive. What a shallow way to think about men as well. (holiday eats) You can make all of these delicious Christmas/holiday foods anytime of year. Just sayin'. Pumpkin pie on the 4th of July. Christmas cookies for Easter. Cranberry sauce (as long as you freeze some berries) on a random day in May. There is no need to feel pressured to make green bean casserole or homemade rolls only in December. The realization that you can enjoy these things at any time of year takes some of the pressure off having to make all of the things at a time of year when your body may be craving rest. It allows you to nourish your body with what it is actually craving instead of stuffing it full of foods you believe only come once a year. (writing) Sitting down to a blank page is like going to work in your underwear. People may like what they see, or they’ll laugh or tell you where to buy a better fitting bra. When we write, especially when we share, we open ourselves to the harsh reality of standing in a room, exposed. (artist's statement) Kelli tells poetic stories that examine the connection between nature and human nature. Stories of love, rebirth, and longing. Stories of secrets hidden away in seashells and cottages of madness. Not content to limit herself, she rambles through themes and styles with the quiet voice of a conversation at midnight. She hopes her poems of solitude can give the reader a place to rest, away from the noise and chaos of the world. (aesthetic) I wish I could invite you into an aesthetic. We could sit in a white room on a blush couch free of crumbs and random letters. Drink sweet tea in matching cups, served on a wooden tray without stains of other lives. A perfectly neutral space where you could rest your feet on a plush pouf, instead of regrets. There would be order &amp; the perfect border of white space hiding closets full of autobiographies &amp; sharp knives. I could invite you into an aesthetic lie, but really, where’s the fun in that? (a happiness collection) I once bought a silly, realistic-looking, plastic rooster. I thought it would be funny to set it by the front door of our new house. As people visited, they obviously noticed the rooster. And thought that it meant I had a love of roosters. Pretty soon I was getting roosters for gifts. Rooster prints, rooster doorstops, ceramic roosters. Before I knew it I had a whole collection of roosters.
The problem was, it really wasn’t my thing. I didn’t have any great love for roosters. Sometimes life can be like that. It starts throwing things at you that you really don’t want. You find yourself spending your days doing things you don’t enjoy. Your life becomes a collection of things you didn’t choose. Don’t live a life with a bunch of roosters you don’t want. Clear out all of the things that don’t bring you joy and live a life that makes you happy. In 2023 let's choose to live.
Let's choose fun over fear.
Let's create for ourselves rather than for likes.
Let's make terrible art.
Let's laugh at stupid shit.
Let's love and be open to others without the fear of rejection.
Let's choose people who go out of their way to show us they care over the assholes who treat us like burdens.
Let's make the world a better place.
Let's promote what we love rather than giving space to what we hate.
Let's look at each other with compassion.
Let's be vulnerable.
Let's be soft.
Let's realize that each person is inherently worthy of our love.
Let's realize that we are the people inherently worthy of love.
Let's create a circle of acceptance.
I love you all. I hope you carry that love and just a dash of hope into 2023.
Happy New Year! (4 Am) - It's almost 4am.
4am is the hour when we admit all of the feelings we have that we tell ourselves we shouldn't
All of the truths we swallow down when the sun is up and everything seems like it will work out
4am tells us were fools to believe any of it
4am makes us face ourselves in the darkness like Luke facing himself in that cave on Dagobah. We realize we are really Darth Vader even though we thought we were a Jedi at heart.
4am is the hour of facing our dark side and realizing it's who we really are. 8/7/22 (fuck off) To the "agree to disagree" crowd
I am respectful of your beliefs and your way of life until those beliefs impact others.Human rights are not up for debate.
Whether they be reproductive rights, or Igbq rights, or equal rights for people of color or women, these things are not up for debate and I will not agree to disagree with you on any one of them.
If you try to shove your beliefs into my vagina and fuck me over with them, I will not "agree to disagree."
And don't come at me with your mask and vaccine mandate false equivalency arguments. My unplanned pregnancy does not affect you. Your covid breath affects me.
Just so we're clear on this. (gendered sports) I have a solution for the people who are so pressed about trans women in sports. If it's a sport like swimming or running where people are timed, stop dividing people by gender and instead make time categories regardless of gender. Your average time in whatever race is however many seconds? You're in whatever category for that time. Gender doesn't have to come into it. Only speed.
There. I solved that problem. Stay tuned for more of my very wise solutions to invented problems. (on taking advice) Read all the booklists you want. Take all the suggestions, keep up to date on what's on the bestseller lists - but in the end, leave room for what you enjoy. If a book isn't speaking to you, no matter how well reviewed, how often suggested, then choose to put it down without finishing it. There are not enough years in a life to read all of the books and if you spend too many of them reading what's on other people's lists, you may never be able to compile your own.
I would say a similar thing about any kind of list or advice. Read all of it you want, take what you need, but in the end you know yourself and what will work for you best. Reading a writer's list of what worked to get them writing may be a great place to start, but in the end only you know what works for you. Maybe they woke at dawn to write 100 pages before lunch. Maybe you sit down after lunch and write 20 pages. So, you decide to start waking at dawn, only you're not a morning person so you're falling asleep and not writing anything at all. Listen to your mind and body. It knows what works for you. Someone who has never even heard of you can't tell you how to work or play. (media consumption) How many corporate slogans, jingles, live rent free in your head? How much are you affected by the ads you see without even realizing? How much do we allow advertising and corporations to decide the things that bond is together as a society? TV shows we watch, movies we've seen, songs chosen for us to hear on the radio, jingles and ads that are the glue of generations. Products we all remember from the specific point in history that was our childhood shared with our cohorts. How much does this shape our collective experience? How are we united by things we never chose? How are we divided by them?
How much have I been altered by the media I consumed as a child/teenager? All the books, movies, TV shows, and love songs? How much of my dialogue was written in a script in the 80s? Are my expectations of relationships based in a scripted, unrealistic ideal?
]]></description><link>03-flowers/passing-thoughts.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/Passing Thoughts.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 04:05:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/thoughts.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/thoughts.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 Reading Log]]></title><description><![CDATA[January
Too Loud a Solitude - Bohumil Hrabal
February
Murder Most Actual - Alexis Hall
Ballad of Songbirds and Snakes - Suzanne Collins
March
Fairy Tale - Stephen King
May
Good Luck with That - Kristen Higgins
June
Role Playing - Cathy Yardley
July
Five Little Pigs - Agatha Christie
We Could Make this Place Beautiful - Maggie Smith
August
The Outsider - Stephen King
Tender Buttons - Gertrude Stein
September A Raisin in the Sun - Lorraine Hansberry
October
Poet Warrior - Joy Harjo
November
Women Who Run With the Wolves - Clarissa Pinkola Estés
A Room of One’s Own - Virginia Woolf
Why Ghosts Appear - Todd Shimoda
December
Olivia Strauss is Running Out of Time - Angela Brown
]]></description><link>04-rabbit-holes/bibliophile/2023-reading-log.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">04 Rabbit Holes/Bibliophile/2023 Reading Log.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 03:52:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2022 Reading Log]]></title><description><![CDATA[January
Dialogues with Rising Tides - Kelli Russell Agodon (poetry)
Spoiler Alert - Olivia Dade
Before the Coffee Gets Cold - Toshikazu Kawaguchi
Some Things I Still Can't Tell You - Misha Collins (poetry)
Catching Fire - Suzanne Collins
February
6. What We Don't Talk About When We Talk About Fat - Aubrey Gordon
7. Helplessly Hoping - B. Alan Hart
8. Giovanni's Room - James Baldwin
9. Men Explain Things to Me - Rebecca SolnitMarch
10. The Sentence - Louise Erdrich
11. What Angels Fear - C.S. Harris
12. Health at Every Size - Lindo BaconApril
13. Mockingjay - Suzanne Collins
14. Cloud Cuckoo Land - Anthony DoerrMay
15. Call Us What We Carry - Amanda Gorman (poetry)
16. The Glass Hotel - Emily St. John Mandel
17. Tales from the Cafe - Toshikazu Kawaguchi
18. Unmasked - Paul Holes
19. Treasury of Norse Mythology - Donna Jo Napoli
20. The Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. HydeJuneJuly
21. Sea of Tranquility - Emily St. John Mandel
22. One By One - Ruth Ware
23. Woke Racism - John McWhorterAugust
24. All the Lies They Did Not Tell - Pablo Trincia
25. The Lost Village - Camilla StenSeptember
26. Upgrade - Blake Crouch
27. Husband Material - Alexis HallOctober
28. Little Fires Everywhere - Celeste Ng
29. The Year of the Witching - Alexis HendersonNovember
30. The Invisible Life of Addie LaRue - V.E. SchwabDecember
31. Enough Already - Valerie Bertinelli
32. A man - Keiichiro Hirano
33. A Christmas Carol - Charles Dickens
34. The Hate U Give - Angie Thomas
35. Hourglass Museum - Kelli Russell Agodon
36. Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep - Philip K. Dick
37. Girls Who Wear Glasses - Jennifer Inglis]]></description><link>04-rabbit-holes/bibliophile/2022-reading-log.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">04 Rabbit Holes/Bibliophile/2022 Reading Log.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 03:52:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2021 Reading Log]]></title><description><![CDATA[January
Between the World and Me - Ta-Nehisi Coates
Martyrs of a Certain Belief - Anthony Desmond (poems)
February
Ready Player Two - Ernest Cline
How to Do Nothing - Jenny O'Dell
March
Let's Go (So We Can Get Back) - Jeff Tweedy
Why We Can't Sleep - Ada Calhoun
April
7. It's Not All Downhill From Here - Terri McMillanMay
8. Zen Mind, Beginner's Mind - Shunryu Suzuki
9. How to Write One Song - Jeff Tweedy
10. The Creative Habit - Twyla Tharp
11. Wintering - Katherine MayJune
12. No one is Talking About This - Patricia LockwoodJuly
13. The Hunting Party - Lucy Foley
14. One to Watch - Kate Stayman LondonAugust
15. The Guest List - Lucy Foley
16. Chosen Poems Old and New - Audre Lorde
17. Resonance - Alice Ewens
18. Collected Poems - Audre Lorde
19. Night Sky with Exit Wounds - Ocean VuongSeptember
20. Boyfriend Material - Alexis Hall
21. Fear Country - Alice Ewens (poems)
22. Whisperings of the Wild and Wilting - Lyn Patterson (poems)
23. Altered Traits - Daniel Goleman, Richard Davidson
24. The Memory Police - Yoko Ogawa
25. Beach Read - Emily HenryOctober
26. Snow - John Banville
27. The Bone Houses - Emily Lloyd-Jones
28. Overcoming Unwanted Intrusive Thoughts - Sally Winston, Martin Self
29. The Illustrated Man - Ray BradburyNovember
30. Home Before Dark - Riley Sager
31. Whispers and Wild Things - Alice Ewens
32. Everything Sucks and I Hate it Here - Lyn Patterson (poems, zine)
33. Tokyo Ueno Station - Yu Miri
34. Black Girl, Call Home - Jasmine Mans (poems)December
35. Strange Weather in Tokyo - Hiromi Kawakami
36. Julie and Romeo - Jeanne Ray
37. The Tradition - Jericho Brown (poems)
The Hunger Games - Suzanne Collins (a reread but this time I read it with Dylan)
Top 10:
Resonance - Alice Ewens
Let's Go (So We Can Get Back) - Jeff Tweedy
No one is Talking About This - Patricia Lockwood
One to Watch - Kate Stayman London
Boyfriend Material - Alexis Hall
Whispers and Wild Things - Alice Ewens
Whisperings of the Wild and Wilting - Lyn Patterson
The Illustrated Man - Ray Bradbury
The Memory Police - Yoko Ogawa
The Bone Houses - Emily Lloyd-Jones]]></description><link>04-rabbit-holes/bibliophile/2021-reading-log.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">04 Rabbit Holes/Bibliophile/2021 Reading Log.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 03:52:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2020 Reading Log]]></title><description><![CDATA[January:
The Subtle Art of Not Giving a Fuck - Mark Manson
Winter Hours - Mary Oliver
March:
3. Chase Darkness With Me - Billy JensenApril:
4. Normal - Warren Ellis
5. The Roar - A.M. WhiteJune:
6. New and Selected Poems - Mary OliverJuly:
7.The Mysterious Affair at a Styles - Agatha Christie(During this time I started and didn't finish many, many books. My concentration was just shot. Finally it came back and I'm so happy to be reading again!)October:
8. The Midnight Library - Matt Haig
9. The Bluest Eye - Toni Morrison
10. The Haunting of Brynn Wylder - Wendy WebbNovember:
11. The Dead Father's Club - Matt Haig
12. Eleanor Oliphant is Completely Fine - Gail Honeyman
13. A Little History of the World - E.H. GombrichDecember:
14. The Things You Can See Only When You Slow Down - Haemin Sunim
15. Conflict Resolution for Holy Beings - Joy Harjo
16. Journals of Thoreau - Henry David Thoreau]]></description><link>04-rabbit-holes/bibliophile/2020-reading-log.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">04 Rabbit Holes/Bibliophile/2020 Reading Log.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 03:52:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2019 Reading Log]]></title><description><![CDATA[January:
Murder on the Orient Express - Agatha Christie
Process: The Writing Lives of Great Authors - Sarah Stodola
Parable of the Sower - Octavia Butler
February:
4. Persepolis - Marjane Satrapi
5. The Season of Passage - Christopher Pike
6. Sour Grapes - Willam Carlos Williams (poetry)
7. The Graveyard Book - Neil Gaiman
8. A Little Book of Japanese Contentments - Erin Nimi LonghurstMarch:
9. The Lathe of Heaven - Ursula Le Guin
10. Persepolis 2 - Marjane Satrapi
11. A Garden Once Lush - B. Alan Hart
12. Odd and the Frost Giants - Neil GaimanApril:
13. Annihilation - Jeff VanderMeer
14. City of Fate - Nikola PierceMay:
15. Less - Andrew Sean Greer
16. When Morning Comes - Arushi RainaJune:
17. The Haunting of Hill House - Shirley Jackson
18. The Dark Heart (True Crime) - Joakim PalmkvistAugust:
19. We Have Always Lived in the Castle - Shirley Jackson
20. Tales of the City - Armistead Maupin
21. The Honours - Tim ClareSeptember:
22. More Tales of the City - Armistead Maupin
23. Pines - Blake CrouchOctober:
24. Over the Top - Jonathan Van Ness
25. The Giver - Lois LowryNovember:
26. Not Your Princess - anthology
27. Further Tales of the City - Armistead MaupinDecember:
28. Unspeakable Things - Jess Lourey
29. If You Tell - Gregg Olsen
30. Complete Sherlock Holmes - Sir Arthur Conan Doyle (read over 5 years or so, but finally finished this year.)
31. Misguided Journey - B. Alan Hart
32. The Little Book of Funerals - C S Hughes]]></description><link>04-rabbit-holes/bibliophile/2019-reading-log.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">04 Rabbit Holes/Bibliophile/2019 Reading Log.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 03:52:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2018 Reading Log]]></title><description/></item><item><title><![CDATA[08 Creative Ideas]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="20230331_beautiful_things.JPG" src="media/art/20230331_beautiful_things.jpg" target="_self">
Chicago
She - women’s names and songs called “she” or “her”
heavy weather - weather songs
make a zine**
design stickers
writing workshop
podcastnewsletter (or zine as newsletter?)Artist Trading Cards
52 (things) with a deck of cards
small pieces/mini collagesbook covers
album covers (for my made up band names)]]></description><link>01-seeds/08-creative-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/08 Creative Ideas.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 14:03:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/art/20230331_beautiful_things.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/art/20230331_beautiful_things.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concerts]]></title><description><![CDATA[08/29/25: My Chemical Romance
11/25: Waterparks]]></description><link>00-kelli-anna/concerts.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">00 Kelli Anna/Concerts.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:58:38 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/concert.jpeg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/concert.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[concert]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/concert.jpeg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/concert.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/concert.jpeg</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:51:46 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/concert.jpeg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/concert.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[00.0 Kelli Anna]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a data-href="00.1 The Writer" href="00-kelli-anna/00.1-the-writer.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">00.1 The Writer</a><br>
<a data-href="Concerts" href="00-kelli-anna/concerts.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Concerts</a><br>
<a data-href="I Love" href="00-kelli-anna/i-love.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">I Love</a><br>
<a data-href="What Feeds Me" href="00-kelli-anna/what-feeds-me.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">What Feeds Me</a><br>
<a data-href="Women I Admire" href="00-kelli-anna/women-i-admire.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Women I Admire</a>]]></description><link>00-kelli-anna/00.0-kelli-anna.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">00 Kelli Anna/00.0 Kelli Anna.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 17:31:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Drawing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/drawing.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/drawing.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/Drawing.jpg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:56:54 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/drawing.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/drawing.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Denial]]></title><description><![CDATA[Logan had just gotten a haircut that morning. He’d called his friend Aisha and made plans to meet her for lunch next week. He’d bought his dog a new leash and collar and told Aisha he was going to take the dog for more walks to get them both in better shape. Three days later he washed up on the shore of Lake Michigan with no signs of foul play, his death eventually ruled accidental. He’d been drunk, maybe he fell in, it happened all the time. Aisha kept his dog, attended his memorial, and wept with his family at the seemingly pointless way of things, and life in the city went on. Only the man who read about it in on the Chicago Tribune website a week later knew the truth, scowling as he put his keys in his pocket and went out for another night on the town.As he passed bar after bar, the streetlights making the night feel like day, he puzzled over whether or not he could count this “Logan” as the first. It felt a bit hollow, a bit unfinished. It certainly hadn’t felt like he was sure the first one would have felt. He had envisioned everything about the night, right down to the Nirvana t-shirt he had worn, the one with the smiley face, but that was the only thing that had gone as planned. He was supposed to have persuaded the guy to get in his car, taken him to Osterman Beach and filleted him like a fresh caught trout before he dumped him into Lake Michigan as fish food, but this “Logan” had ruined the whole thing with his $200 haircut and his problems and his secrets. This “Logan” who had denied him his relief.He pulled his freshly detailed car up to the curb outside of The Green Mill, tried to calm his racing heart, and let his eyes scan the crowd for the loner, the person no one would miss right away. The man with just the right amount of stumble to his gait that signaled he had drank more than he planned and now needed a ride home to sleep it off. This is where it had all gone wrong with that “Logan.” He should have sensed the air of hopelessness about his prey, but instead he had rolled down his window, offered the man in the clean khakis a ride, “You’ll wait awhile for an Uber, dude, might as well hop in and I’ll drive you for less,” he had told Logan. And Logan had taken the bait. He’d collapsed into the back seat, but then instead of an address, he’d asked to be taken to The Belmont Rocks.“What do you want to go there for at this time of night? Come on, man, let me take you home,” he had kindly told Logan. “No charge. You just seem like you could use a good night’s rest.”“I could use a lot of things, but advice from a guy making his living driving a knock-off Uber isn’t one of them. I want to go to the rocks. I want to see the water. I want to remember.”So he’d driven him to the lake shore. It was the plan anyway, right? So what if the guy was going there willingly instead of demanding to know where he was being taken? He was still in control. He was still the only one who knew the ending, so he’d taken Logan to the rocks. He’d followed him as he’d gotten out of the car and weaved his way to the limestone wall that lined the lake shore. He’d watched as Logan watched the water, pulled at his hair, and cried out in an agony that came from some ancient place in his DNA, and he’d felt compelled to know where this grief originated. He wanted to know if he’d be doing his victim a favor rather than robbing him of something precious.“Hey, man, do you want to talk about it? Come away from the rocks, I’m afraid you’ll fall in. Maybe it would help to talk to someone, especially a stranger, you know? Leave it with someone who doesn’t even know ya. Then I’ll take you home. Just step back and let’s talk.”Logan had backed up a few feet, run his fingers through that too perfect hair again, and had said in almost a whisper, “It’s all a lie. It’s all been a lie.”The city lights stood at a distance as if waiting to be invited to the conversation, the moon&nbsp; hung low and tried to pull at the lake that refused to be guided by gravity, a star or two did its best to compete against the ingenuity of man, and the driver felt his fingers twitch at the thought of the knife in his pocket. He prompted his prey, “What’s a lie?”“All of it!” Logan yelled as the water hit the rocks with a surprising force. “My whole life! These pressed clothes, my high-rise condo! The whole fucking thing! This place! This place is the only truth. The only place where I can feel free.”“The rocks? Why here, man? What’s here for you but crumbling limestone and pollution?”“They used to come here when they had no where else to go. People like me. They came here because it’s where they could be a part of something. I don’t know that I’m a part of anything! No one knows who I am! It’s supposed to be ok now, you know? It’s supposed to be accepted! But here I am with a job and a dog and friends, and the risk of losing everything if I tell anyone. I’d rather sacrifice myself to the ghosts than keep on this way!”“Ah, I see. In the closet, huh? Why? No one cares anymore, right? They even have that rainbow shit at Target now. They have that show with the five dudes who make people pretty. It’s all good, my man.” Why was he trying to talk this guy down? Why did he genuinely want him to feel ok with who he was? He came here to cut him open and count the rings of his life, not to teach him self love, but he knew what it was to live with secrets and he knew what it took to quiet them and keep them hidden. Mostly he wanted the guy to not want to die so the killing would satisfy the need to take something someone dearly wanted to keep.“You don’t understand. No one understands! I tried! I tried to tell Aisha. I tried to tell my mom, but they both brushed it away. They told me I just needed to meet the right girl. There was a partner at my firm who came out two months ago. They finally found a reason to let him go last week. It’s not as easy as you think! It’s not easy at all.”With that Logan slumped to the ground. His shoulders heaved as the lake soaked into his creases and the breeze ruffled his hair. “The people who came here were braver than I can ever be. Too many of them paid the ultimate price.”
“So this is how you honor them? By giving up? By throwing yourself into a watery grave? This is how you remember the ones who gave everything and were left to waste away? This is how you honor your past? Man, I think maybe you’re better than that. I think you came here to let the ghosts guide you. Not to join them, but to be joined to them. But what do I know? I’m just a knock-off Uber driver in a vintage Nirvana shirt.”Logan gave a shadow of a smile, “Vintage? I saw that same shirt at Target last week, right next to the rainbow shit, as you call it.”Logan walked onto the rocks and stared out at the darkness waiting to swallow him whole. He exhaled the last of the whiskey he’d drank an hour earlier, and said, “You know, I flirted with a very nice man tonight. I just bought my dog a new leash.” He was silent for a few crashes of the tide.“Maybe you’re right. Maybe it was fate that put me in your car tonight. Maybe… maybe I can find a way to stop pretending. If not, I guess this place will still be here next week. Take me home. Please.” He turned to face the driver only to be met with moonlight reflecting off a blade just inches from his face.“What the… Why??”“I’m sorry, man, really. It’s not you. In fact, I thought about just taking you home, but it has to be tonight, see? It was supposed to be tonight. But, this has nothing to do with who you are, really. I’m a lotta things, but I’m not a bigot. It just had to be tonight. It has to be now. I’ve waited too long. I’m really sorry.”“Then why didn’t you just let me kill myself? Why talk me out of it?”“It has to be me who decides! It has to be me who does the killing!”The driver slammed his hand against the steering wheel as he continued to scan the crowd outside of The Green Mile. He came back here because it was where it had all gone wrong last time. This is where he needed to be to make it right. All because of Mr. Perfect. All because that “Logan’s” foot had slipped on the damn wet limestone right before the knife had found his flesh and he fell as if in slow motion into the waves of Lake Michigan. He’d screamed for help. He’d flailed and fought the tide, but eventually it won. The driver had just stood there, watching. Hadn’t reached out a hand, hadn’t called for help, hadn’t grabbed his cell and dialed 911. Just watched as the body of his first victim was battered against the rocks, his $200 haircut turning into pulp, and puzzled over whether or not it counted. Were you a killer if all you did was let a person die? That was still what bothered him as he sat watching the last of the patrons stream out of the bar. Would this be number one or number two? He brushed a piece of lint from his new t-shirt, scanned the crowd, and vowed that this time he wouldn’t let some sad sack control the evening. This time he would be the one to do the talking and the taking. This time he would be the one to decide who lives or dies.He rolled down his window, “You’ll wait awhile for an Uber, dude, might as well hop in and I’ll drive you for less,” he said to the man with less than perfect hair. And to his delight, the man crawled in, gave him an address, laid his head back, and closed his eyes. The driver put the car in gear, smiled, and drove east with his offering to the lake.*Written for Creative Writing summer 2023, Professor BrunigSubmitted to Spire magazine, December 2023
published in Spire Magazine 2024]]></description><link>03-flowers/short-stories/denial.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/short stories/Denial.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:49:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bottled Up Wishes]]></title><description><![CDATA[We once drank starlight from fluted champaign glasses, on a balcony overlooking the lives of ten million people. We poured love into each other’s ears and let the sheets pool onto the floor as the streetlights threw shadows over bare skin. We drank black coffee at midnight and ate toast over the Sunday crossword, laughing when we could only fill in a third of the squares. I wrote poetry on his palm in purple ink so he could put me in his pocket when his hands got cold on the corner waiting for the bus. He felt like forever until the morning I clearly heard him say, “I wish you would just shut the fuck up so I can tell you goodbye.”“What did you say?” I asked, shocked because just last night he had told me how you loved the way I could tell a story.“I didn’t say anything, but I do need to get going to the bus stop.”“Elliot, you just told me to shut the fuck up. I heard you.”Elliot turned an early sunset shade of pink and stammered, “I, I, I don’t think I did. I do have to get to the bus though.”It wasn’t long before I was sleeping alone on perfectly placed sheets and throwing the crossword in the recycling bin untried. Elliot had told me goodbye a few days later. The forever kind, not the off to the bus stop kind. I suppose I should have told him at some point over the eight months we were together that I can hear other people’s wishes, but it just hadn’t come up. I had honestly thought he might be the only man in the city who never wished for anything. It had been such a relief just to sit with him and not hear a constant stream of things he could never have - a better job, a woman with bigger boobs, a catamaran in the Bahamas. It hurt like hell when the first thing he wished for was for me to shut up.I gave myself a week to stream whole seasons of heartbreak and to sleep wrapped in the dress shirts he had left behind, inhaling what I knew was detergent but pretending it was him. I knew I was healing when I picked up a romance novel and lost myself in the steam. I went back to work the next day and only cried a little when I heard the girl at the next desk say, “I wish my husband would stop wanting to cuddle all the time. I just need some space.”Oh the wishes of the married and secure who didn’t remember what it was like to reach over in the middle of the night and feel nothing but a cold spot and a sense of something missing. Oh how I wished I could accept that cuddling in her place.As I left work for the day I couldn’t resist stopping at her desk and saying, “Enjoy it while you have it, sister. It could all be gone tomorrow.”That might be why everyone at my company avoided me at the Christmas party and the annual picnic, but since I was the only one who knew how to fix our archaic computer system, they had to at least pretend to be nice to me at work.I sometimes wish I could bottle all of these wishes and put them on a shelf in my apartment. Admire the different colors and smells of each one. Watch them swirl behind the glass and know that almost none of them will ever come true. I would especially like to capture the wishes of unrequited love. They are so loud and desperate and there are so, so many of them falling from the rooftops of skyscrapers, that I would like to quiet them with a stopper and never let them out into the world again. There are so few unique wishes. It’s almost always for love or to save a dying family member, which is really the same thing in the end. Yet they are all so earnest in their vibrations, they all are so badly desired that I once tried to make one come true, just to see what would happen.I was on the corner of 54th and Franklin on a hell of a summer day, checking my phone for messages from Elliot when I heard it as if it had circled directly into my cochlea. “I wish I had the nerve to tell him that I want to be more than friends.”I looked to my left and saw a young girl in a pretty strawberry dress gazing adoringly at the small, somewhat nerdy boy next to her. The wish weighed so much that I instinctively felt the need to set it down. I walked over to the pair and announced to the young man that the girl would really like to be more than friends. The girl’s eyes widened in horror and her mouth fell open and flapped around like a plastic bag caught in a tree in January.The boy only kept pushing buttons on the game he was playing and said, “Yeah, I know. But I just want things to stay the way they are.”The girl had run off in tears and I had vowed to never get involved with the business of fulfilling wishes again. Well, if you don’t count Elliot and the fact that I did shut the fuck up and allow him to say goodbye. Sometimes it happens accidentally, but it’s not like I have much control over that. I’ve also learned that much like my coworker who would probably feel neglected if her husband actually stopped wanting to cuddle, most people don’t actually want their wishes fulfilled and they feel a sense of guilt when they do get what they want. Well, again, except Elliot who hasn’t bothered to text me or even ask for his dress shirts back, which is a good thing since I took them to Goodwill with a wish that they would find a good home.I was tired of my silent apartment and drinking wine by myself on a balcony meant for two, so I did something I never do - I went to a bar. I avoid bars because the wishes of drunks are&nbsp; generally sex or sports related. Although there is often the one really sad drunk who either wishes his wife hadn’t left him or that he was a better dad to his grown kids. It breaks my heart either way that life only moves in one direction and we can’t undo all the stupid decisions our younger selves made for us.The bar wasn’t too crowded on this Wednesday night and the normal sound of the basketball game on the giant screen TV had been replaced by Lizzo reminding me that I’m a bad bitch who doesn’t need a man. I slid onto a stool and remembered how Lizzo had been Elliot’s favorite for about two months the summer before. I ordered a drink and slid into a memory of how it felt to drink with someone else when you knew that later the empty glasses will sit together on the nightstand while the alcohol lets you whisper your wishes into the hollow of your lover’s collarbone. How I wished that I could channel my inner Lizzo, forget about Elliot, and just take someone home and let the liquor do it’s thing.“I’m sorry you were hurt,” said a voice two stools down.“I’m sorry, what?” I asked.“Elliot. I’m sorry he left you.”I stared at the man with the kind eyes while the night stretched like old leather and I knew then how naked the girl in the strawberry dress had felt when I had exposed her.“I didn’t mention anything about any Elliot.”
“Oh, really? I’m sorry. I must have the wrong person. It must have been someone else in here on the phone. I’m so sorry. Just ignore me. Too many drinks in already,” the man said with a gentle smile and a tilt of his lowball.Could it be true? Could there be another person like me? It couldn’t be a coincidence. It just couldn’t be. So I tried again.“I wish that someone else could hear the wishes that fill the air like gnats on a summer night,” I whispered in my head.I looked at the man. He looked up at me with a slow look of surprise and I caught the slight slur in his silent reply, “I wish that someone would take this weight off of my lungs because they can’t handle even one more day breathing in wishes in this city of so many lonely people.”I slid off my stool and sat down next to him.“I’m Mia,” I said, “and I would love to carry some of that weight so that you can breathe a little easier.”“I’m Arman and while I don’t know you that well yet, I think that Elliot must have been a damned fool.”Just then the door banged open and a young woman huffed into the bar, sat down heavily in a booth, and I knew that we both heard just what kind of a day she had just had.“I wish he would get hit by the 8:00 bus! I wish he would fall off the edge of earth and asphyxiate in space! I wish he would be clawed to death by a million tiny crawfish!”“Here’s to heartbreak, Arman,” I said with a tilt of my Malbec.He clinked his glass to mine, “And to the gift of unfulfilled wishes.”July 8, 2023<img alt="Bottled Up Wishes.png" src="media/writing/bottled-up-wishes.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-flowers/short-stories/bottled-up-wishes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/short stories/Bottled Up Wishes.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:48:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Penance for the Pain]]></title><description><![CDATA[The mirror was an old one, blackened with time, but Lucas could still make out his face in the dim light of the bedroom. He was hideous. His hair had thinned to streaks of an ink pen on a white canvas. A scar of waxy skin covered his right cheek. The red of his eyes was only made worse by the empty bottle at his feet. He carried a constant pain in his right cheek from a rotten molar and he cherished the pain as penance for his sins. He held it tight like a mouthful of Hail Marys, each throb another bead on a black rosary. He flipped up the hood of his sweatshirt and turned away from his reflection, relief flooding through him that this time the mirror hadn’t turned into a windshield flying toward his face, and that he wouldn’t have to look again until tomorrow morning when he’d dress to face another day that didn’t want him in it. Everyday since the accident had been a day that didn’t want him here. He was supposed to have died with them that night, but here he was, preparing for another visit to a couch, a bright room that saw his every flaw, and a man who never listened when Lucas asked him not to look so closely.He walked to the kitchen where he could still smell the memory of steak and Elena’s body wash. He shook out the pills the doctor had prescribed and washed them down with yesterday’s cold coffee. He felt their movement all the way down his throat as if they too wanted to seal off his share of air. He shut his eyes and for an instant the kitchen seemed to melt around him, replaced with a wet street soaking into his pant legs, blood pouring over his hands, and the smell of gas registering like an alarm in his amygdala telling him to flee. His breath quickened and his eyes shot open, searching for five things in the room he could see, hear, and touch, just as the doctor had instructed. When his breath slowed, Lucas grabbed his backpack and set out through his old neighborhood.The potted flowers on the steps of his townhouse were long dead, the chipped paint on the white railing revealed a patina of old metal beneath. As Lucas started down the steps, he shrunk back in horror as the railing turned to bone, the paint into burnt flesh peeling back from muscle and vein. He squeezed his eyes shut as he had learned to do over the past few months. Wait it out. It was just a memory. It was just his damn, messed up memory. He hurried past the melting arm and continued toward the psychiatrist’s office. He could no longer drive or ride in anything with an engine. He no longer trusted anything but his tennis shoes on familiar sidewalks.&nbsp;At the corner shop, Mr. Peterson was putting up a sign advertising a sale on fresh cut steaks. Mr. Peterson’s shop was a staple of the neighborhood run by a gentle, welcoming man who chuckled at local gossip and suddenly remembered something was on sale when a customer didn’t have enough money. Over the years Lucas went from buying candy bars on his way home from school, to stopping in on Friday evenings to buy flowers and cheap wine to take home to Elena. He always remembered to ask Mr. Peterson about his son who was studying at M.I.T. Lucas had heard the pride in Mr. Peterson’s voice and he had hoped he too would one day speak of his own child like that. But his child never became more than blood on a street corner from a dead womb.Mr. Peterson looked up from his sign and gave Lucas a sad smile, “Lucas, it’s been so long. How are you, son? Would you like to come in?”Lucas caught a glimpse of himself in the reflection of the shop window, black holes where his eyes once looked to the future and a twisted mouth that had once made vows of forever rippled in the glass. Lucas didn’t know how Mr. Peterson could stand to look at him with his scars and his shame and his loss dripping like rain water from his skin.“No thank you, Mr. Peterson. I’m sorry. I have somewhere to be,” Lucas mumbled without looking up from the sidewalk. He wouldn’t drag Mr. Peterson into a life of pills, shrinks, and visions of mirrors that shattered over him like shards of windshield glass.This is why he kept his eyes staring forward at the changing stoplights. There were too many people who wanted to see him smile with perfect white teeth and to admit that he was the one who should have had a steering wheel embedded in his chest, since he was the reason Elena had been driving that night when the rain had turned to sleet, and the black road had turned to black ice. Because he had too much to drink. Because he had argued with her over the baby. Only a few more blocks. Only a few more haunted landmarks. He could see the windows in his peripheral vision, bulging outwards to look more closely at his sins. No longer a child on a bicycle in a long stretch of summer, but a monster hiding from the burning of autumn.Slowly the quiet neighborhood melted into a busy business district and Lucas tried to melt into the crowd of people with lives that hadn’t crashed and burned on a January street. When he arrived at the psychiatrist’s office, he stopped underneath the reddening maple to ready himself for what came next. As he watched, the shadows of the leaves became tiny lost souls crawling over the sidewalk. He could almost hear them calling out to him to save them. He closed his eyes at the thought of the soul of his unborn child drifting somewhere, alone, maybe afraid, and he wanted to scoop these tiny shadows into his pocket and take them home. Instead he convinced himself to look away and entered the building for another round of lies. Always “it’s not your fault” and “you can’t blame yourself.” Fuck if he couldn’t. He’d been doing a pretty damn good job of it for months now.Dr. McClellan’s office was blessedly dimly lit. He had no receptionist and the office was always empty at the time of his regular Friday afternoon appointment. He counted the squares on the beige rug while he waited with the magazines on mindfulness, the sign reading, “Please Silence Your Phone,” and the wall clock whose hands never moved. It was always 11:17 on Friday at Dr. McClellan’s office.Within minutes, Dr. McClellan, in his brown blazer and white beard, opened the door to his inner office. He waved Lucas in and settled himself in his leather arm chair, moleskin notebook on his knee, fountain pen in his hand, wireframes perched on the bridge of his nose. Lucas again felt the feeling of time standing still. He sat on the couch opposite the doctor and pulled off the hood of his sweatshirt. He adjusted his sparse hair as he sighed and steeled himself for what he knew was coming.“How have you been feeling, Lucas?” asked Dr. McClellan in his Freudian voice, an accent Lucas couldn’t quite place.“Like my brain is fucking with me. Like nothing is solid. Like everything is just waiting to melt.”“Have you been drinking?”“Yes.”“Too much?”There was no use lying. “Yes.”The doctor only nodded in reply. “Have you been taking your medication?”“Yes. I took some before I left the house.”“Good,” the doctor nodded. “It will help. Do you want to get started where we left off last week? With that night?”Lucas clenched his eyes shut, every cell of his body screaming at him to just get up and leave and not ever tell anyone about that night. Sell the townhouse, move away. Die a slow death alone and rot into the soil, if the ground would have him. Somewhere from outside the office he heard a ticking, like a clock, but the clock was broken he reminded himself. He felt his limbs grow heavy, his thoughts quiet until all of the self hatred was gathered in a pinprick in the center of his forehead. He began to unwind the clock.“I got off early that day. It was a Friday. I stopped at Peterson’s and bought a bottle of champagne for me and a sparkling cider for Elena. A dozen roses. Two fresh steaks. I told Mr. Peterson that we were going to celebrate. I got a raise, we were having a baby. Everything was going to get better. Mr. Peterson was so happy for us. I was so happy for us.”Lucas’s voice seemed to give out. He didn’t think he could continue. The ticking grew louder for a moment, his mind shrank again to a pinprick, and the doctor said in his soothing, unknown voice, “It’s ok, Lucas. You are safe. Thoughts, memories, they can’t hurt you anymore. Just go on.”“Elena was home when I walked in the door, sitting at the kitchen table with a notepad in front of her, writing quickly. When she saw me come in, she turned the pad over and said she wasn’t expecting me so early. I said I wanted to celebrate the baby, and the fact I got a raise. She didn’t seem excited about the raise which seemed strange since we were barely getting by with just the two of us. We needed the money for the baby. I said that. The money will help with the baby. The baby.”Lucas stopped again. A tear slid over the scar of his cheek. He barely felt it. He only felt a slight nudge of his mind from the hand of the doctor, yet no words were spoken.“Elena said I didn’t need to worry about the baby. I didn’t even need to worry about her. She said that she had done something stupid. She had been writing me a letter to tell me. She pushed the notebook to me and I read what she couldn’t say. She wasn’t sure the baby was mine. She was sorry. It wasn’t supposed to have meant anything. I wasn’t supposed to have known. I didn’t know what to say. We had a few problems, sure, but she had seemed happy. We had seemed happy. She sat looking at me with such sad eyes. Such beautiful, sad eyes. I left the house. I walked for an hour. I stopped in the neighborhood pub. I drank too much. In the haze I realized I didn’t care. So what? So what if the baby wasn’t mine? We could still make it work.”Another pause, another nudge, another feeling like he was suspended between ticks of an unseen clock.“I left the pub to walk home. It was just turning from a cold rain to a sleet. As I was waiting to cross the street, I saw a familiar car pass in front of me. Elena was driving our car and she turned her head and saw me. Those sad eyes. They held mine and in that moment I thought everything was going to be ok. We were going to work it all out. Our whole future felt like it was hanging in that moment.”“Did she stop the car? Did she pick you up to take you home?”“No. I… I looked away and saw that the stoplight had turned red while she had been looking at me. I started to wave at her to stop. She looked ahead and slammed on the breaks, but it was too late. The road had turned icy. And… and she slid headfirst into a truck that was turning left in front of her. The sound. Oh, God, Dr. McClellan! The sound! I don’t want to hear the sound!”Lucas could hear the gnashing of metal against metal. He could feel the teeth of the truck biting into the hood of their car. He was there on the sidewalk while Elena was smashing into the steering wheel and ice was falling in his eyes and he was running, running toward her to save what was left.“Lucas. Focus. Look at me. You are at my office. We are just talking. I want you to look at my face, Lucas.”Lucas concentrated on slowing his breath. He looked at the doctor’s face and tried to place where he had seen the man before. Not here in the office, but somewhere. He nodded that he was ready to continue.“I ran up to the car and tried to open the door, but it wouldn’t open. The man in the truck was bleeding, but ok. He got out and tried to help me open the door. We finally managed to get it open and Elena… Elena was, hardly Elena. The airbag hadn’t gone off. She was…”“It’s ok, Lucas. You don’t have to tell me those details now. You don’t have to look so closely at her right now. Let’s just move on to what happened next.”Tears streamed down Lucas’s face and mixed with the freezing rain on a couch on a street in a winter in an autumn, and he decided not to look away.“The man in the truck and I pulled her out of the car. There was so much blood. It was everywhere. The man said we needed to move away from the crash because he could see gas leaking and it might be dangerous. We lifted Elena from the street and I could hear sirens in the distance. We laid her down on the sidewalk. Her chest, her chest… nothing but blood. As the paramedics arrived, the fire started. It was so hot even from that distance. I felt like I was melting&nbsp; in spite of the sleet. The paramedics took Elena and I climbed in the back of the ambulance. The firetruck was just pulling in as we pulled out. Sirens screaming. Maybe I was screaming. The paramedics tried. They did! They tried! But there was no Elena left. There was only her blood mixed with our baby on the sheets. They told me she was dead at the hospital. I looked at my watch. 11:17. 11:17 on a Friday night. Because of me.”“Lucas, why do you think it’s because of you? What did you do?”“I left. I got drunk. I should have stayed and talked it out. She wouldn’t have been driving on the icy streets to look for me if I had been a fucking man and stayed and worked it out with her!”The doctor handed Lucas a familiar piece of notebook paper. “Or not. Read this, Lucas.”Lucas unfolded the paper and saw Elena’s slanted handwriting. It was the letter she had been writing, only she had added to it after he left for the pub. Lucas read that while Elena had thought the other man didn’t matter to her, he had. That she was leaving Lucas to be with him. That she was sorry. He refolded the paper and looked at the doctor, who looked much less like Sigmund Freud than he had when Lucas came in.“She was leaving me? She wasn’t coming to pick me up that night? She was leaving to be with him? I don’t understand. That’s not what I remember at all.”“Do you remember when you first came to see me you described what had happened? That you had gotten drunk and Elena came to get you at the bar? She had been angry with you for drinking when she needed you at home. How you had caused the accident? All I saw was a young man with PTSD and a head full of false memories. When the standard therapy wasn’t working, I thought you would be a good candidate for a new trial therapy. We haven’t been giving you Xanax. We have been microdosing you with a mild hallucinogenic which has proven very effective in the treatment of PTSD.”“But you told me I was taking Xanax. You lied to me! Isn’t that against some kind of Hippocratic oath?”
“Do you remember that you agreed to be a part of a PTSD study? You agreed to undergo experimental treatment. I have your signature here.”“I don’t know. I don’t remember. I don’t know. I… I… She was leaving me. It wasn’t my baby. I wasn’t with her in the car when it happened. But I remember it so clearly! I have this scar.” Lucas ran his hands over his face, feeling only smooth skin, ran his hands through his thick, unkempt hair. “I really don’t know what’s happening. The pills! Is that why I’ve been seeing such weird shit?”“PTSD has been known to cause false memories. The hallucinations were an unexpected side effect of the medication that I hoped would resolve itself before now, especially the view you had of yourself. It seems you somehow developed an outer perception of yourself that you felt matched the inner you. Very interesting, actually.”Lucas grabbed his hair in his hands and looked again at the beige carpet where Elena now lay as if asleep. He began to wail like that January night as he slid from the couch to the floor and cradled her in his arms.“I’m sorry, Elena. I’m sorry I couldn’t save you. I’m sorry I couldn’t let you go before now.” He saw every detail of her flawless skin before her image dissolved and he was left kneeling in an ordinary office on an everyday Friday. The doctor reached out a hand and placed it on Lucas’s shoulder.“Now we begin the work of healing.”The doctor was just an average man, the room an average room, the silence not as deep, the ticking just a regular wall clock. Lucas nodded and sat back on the couch.“I can’t say that I understand anything that’s happened. I can’t say today what’s even real. It wasn’t my fault, but Elena deserved so much better. It all feels unresolved. It all feels wrong. Can you help me make sense of it?”“I will certainly try, Lucas.”As he left the office and walked home down the same uneven sidewalks, Lucas still wasn’t sure that the shadows weren’t trying to pull him under, but he felt the clock begin to move forward again. It was Friday at noon, the beginning of fall. He stopped in front of Mr Petersons’s shop, and caught his reflection in the window. Just a broken man with shaggy brown hair, teeth that needed brushing, and a body that could use a good meal. Lucas hesitated, pushed open the door, heard the familiar jingle of the bell, and stepped inside.August 7, 2023]]></description><link>03-flowers/short-stories/penance-for-the-pain.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/short stories/Penance for the Pain.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:47:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ink Stains]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img alt="Copy of Copy of Copy of Wordmark Substack-8.png" src="media/writing/copy-of-copy-of-copy-of-wordmark-substack-8.png" target="_self">It was the way everything was ending. The way everything was over before I could fully appreciate the beauty of it all. The lights, the stage, the audience, the way they hung on every word. Over. Time to return to the underlying hum of the everyday.I stood in the hotel room for the last time. The weeks and months spinning around me like the color of old paper and I breathed in every dust mote. I tried to grasp every emotion that had made me want to write and share in the first place. I had written a novel. I had written a novel that people wanted to read. I had written a novel that people wanted to read and I taken it on a tour. And people had come to listen as I gave voice to my own words. They had stepped up to tables with the book cradled to their chest like a precious memory and I had listened as they gave my words a new voice. Listened as they told me how the story had moved them to tears. How it had settled into their bones and inspired them to make something of their own. To create something with their hands. To put their own piece of something out to the world. I had hugged them, held their hands, wiped away tears, watched their eyes light up when they talked about their own art. I had seen their art for myself. Carried carefully in folders and notebooks and read from screens. And I had cheered on every one. From the shockingly bad to the earth shattering good. Each one was a masterpiece and an homage to my own work, which I had only dreamed would light a spark when I was alone in a dark room with only the words to guide me.Weeks and months, tables and rooms, stages and hotels, and now... quiet. There had been friendship. Seven authors on one tour of book conventions across the country, across the globe. Seven people with different stories and styles and reasons for putting their words in order. Seven friends. Some better, some worse, but all becoming something to each other in the months of travel, exhaustion, elation and wonder. What now? Would these new friendships carry into the everyday? Would they survive the heartbreak and joy and breakfast and writer’s block of the day to day? Living on separate coasts, separate continents?Survive the introverted, focused life of a writer all alone at a keyboard playing out the lives of people having much more exciting existences than the writers themselves? Typing all of the things they could never be or say onto a little screen in a little room in a little life? For months these seven strangers had been someone else. We had lived the lives we had only dared to write about. And now... would there be enough to hold us together?I thought about all of this as I stood in a white room full of white furniture. White flowers on the white tabletop. I was a bruise of black clothing in this perfect room. I was a bruise of black moods in my other life. Every pure thing that came along was left stained by the sadness I wore like rainwater on my skin. The fact that I had managed to write a book that made people better instead of sad was nothing short of a miracle. My life was empty and black and the only place I felt I fit was in that small dark room in front of that screen writing about people who were infinitely happier than I was. I was an imposter on this book tour. I had laughed with the others and listened to their fears. I had leant a shoulder for tears and I had somehow, I still have no idea how, held onto my own. For once I hadn’t been the sad girl. I had been the inspiration. I had been the happy. I had been the joy. I had felt the joy. Away from everything familiar that made me feel like darkness, like night moving in, like a black spot in a white room. Which one was real? The person I had always been or the one I had become in a few short months? Who would I meet when I got back home? Who would the few remaining people see?What had he seen? Late nights when we sat in each other’s space, among the things that only meant something to us. Me in his room among the ink and color and storyboards. Listening to his soul pour from the speakers when he played the music that pushed him to draw his stories. Among his holy sweaters and ill fitting t-shirts. What had he seen? When he came to my room, a bottle in hand, a sheepish grin, a shrug when I mentioned our early morning. When he sat among my fresh book purchases, when he listened to the sadness pouring from my speakers. When he looked right at me and I was sure he saw the darkness and didn’t care, maybe even found comfort there. What had he seen? Did it matter now that it was over? Tomorrow we all boarded our own flights to be scattered to the winds, and this would only live inus as a remember when.I didn’t even know if he saw anything other than a kindred spirit in an awkward situation. The other five were real humans. Real people who could discuss stocks and interest rates and where they were vacationing next summer with their real life families. With their real life friends. They were solid and alive. But he was more fluid, more hazy, more ghostlike, more like the darkness that drifted into my brain when I was alone with my words for too long. Was I just a drinking buddy distraction for nights he’d had enough of the solid people? Was I the only one who felt there might be more? Would I board my plane tomorrow and someday write an ending that sold a book but left me empty?Back to the white room, to the bright day, to the glare of tomorrow shining in the window that dominated the room and brought the strange city right to my feet. A view that brought me right to my knees. How could I go back to my tiny life, alone with the darkness? Maybe I could just keep boarding planes and living in sterile rooms while I wrote about people in love. Maybe I could hold the reality at bay with my pointed words.A knock jarred me out of my mind and back into that too white room. A turn of the doorknob, a peek around the door, a breath of relief that it’s just him. No bottle. No sheepish grin, no shrug at the late hour. Just the sunlight on his hair and a genuine look of worry over his face. Come in, how was your last day, are you packed, are you ready, what will you do next, can you believe this view?Until I let one drop of the despair escape. Just one drop of overwhelm running over a cheek and he’s there. Arms wrapped around the black bruise in the too white room. There in solid form with a whisper of comfort and a hint of darkness hidden well beneath his holy sweater. A smell like old paper and ink and the coffee he must have just finished before he knocked on my door. A smell like ancient places I dreamed I had once walked in other lives I couldn’t confirm. I couldn’t let go. Even as he whispered that it was ok and that he wasn’t going anywhere, I couldn’t let go. Even as he promised we would stay in touch, as he promised those late nights hadn’t just been about loneliness. Even as heechoed my fear of what came next, I couldn’t let go of the place I had arrived after so many miles. He stood steady, arms only holding tighter, sweater only getting wetter, the white room only growing darker as the sun dipped behind the city.What’s next?Whatever we want. Wherever we want. Look at me.I can’t. I can’t let you see me.I see you. I have seen you for months. I see you. Look at me.{ Slowly, eyes meeting eyes. }I see you and I only want to come closer. I only want to sleep in your night.
I only want you to stay in my reach.
I only want to love you.Can you?I already do.And there in his grey eyes was a hint of moonlight meeting my night. There in his lips was the promise of just a hint of light to guide me. There in his touch was the healing of the bruises. The city rose up to meet us as we sank into the too white bed, two ink stains on fresh paper.November 27, 2022]]></description><link>03-flowers/short-stories/ink-stains.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/short stories/Ink Stains.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:46:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024 City Lights]]></title><description><![CDATA[over his left shoulder
city lights
on off on
there and gone
rhythmic brilliancea taste of downtown
I want to savor
it all at oncethe whole scene
somewhere
on the other side
of his hair
curled at his neckunder the breath
and sweat I am here
and there and herebeneath a heartbeat
and there
above the skylineAugust 11, 2024]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2024-city-lights.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2024 City Lights.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:56:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024 Marble Gardens (Sestina)]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let's write poetry on our palms in blue ink,
like cheat notes for a midterm on existence.
Let's lie in marble gardens, study the curves
that contour lifetimes. Paint scars and realities
one stroke at a time, naked on stretched canvas,
watercolors bleeding on the very edge of hunger.We'll carry our poems and collaborate our hunger.
Tattoo our desires with each other's ink
on our bodies made to be each other's canvas.
Paint me into your vision of existence.
Compose me from your synonyms for reality.
Sketch in thick charcoal my every curve.I will take you in and fit your words to my curves,
create ballads to the way your insatiable hunger
awaits what falls from my fountain pen of realities.
Together we will create museums of blue ink
and stone to prove the facts of our existence,
like a finger painting of pink petals on old canvas.Pink petals covering the scars of a used canvas,
raining over intertwined fingers, filling the curves
on a path carved by the unlikely existence
of two people in a world of eight billion hungry
mouths desiring to consume marble and ink
as cheat notes guiding them to gatekept realities.Through watercolor soliloquies, we release realities
into a world tired of staring at a blank, white canvas,
trying to make sense of the ever changing ink
blot tests of continuous existential crisis, curve
balls and red tape allowing for rampant hunger.
Let our words of desire create a new existence.Here in this garden, we create an artist's existence
through touch and fingertips exploring realities.
We quench our own thirst and feed a deep hunger
for tomorrows roughly sketched on canvas,
and outlined on the page in cursive curves -
a love story of two, inspiring the world through ink.Let's write realities on our palms in blue ink,
explore a hunger for scars in our curves -
render another existence on stretched canvas.March 30, 2024Original:let's write poetry on
our palms in blue ink
cheat notes for a
midterm on existencelie in marble gardens
study the curves
that contour a lifetimepaint scars and truths
one stroke at a time
until we are naked
on stretched canvas -watercolors blending on
the very edge of hunger<img alt="marble_gardens.jpg" src="media/writing/marble_gardens.jpg" target="_self">April 6, 2022]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2024-marble-gardens-(sestina).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2024 Marble Gardens (Sestina).md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:52:37 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/marble_gardens.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/marble_gardens.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024 You Are Not the Sunrise]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are not the sunrise.
You are the remains
of last nights rain on asphalt.As much at fault as pitter patter
raindrops dropping skitter skatter
apologies from your dry tongue.Old weather glints in the sun
and we ask whether what was lost
is worth the cost of holding on
until another lightning round.But then we are not the sunrise.
We are eyes closed to fate, predictors
of the coming hate sewing
a blanket of night. Sowing chance
in the space between holding tight
and the frozen distance of overdue
escape. I mistook you for the dawn,
but you were the light of a dying star.You are not the sunrise,
but a grey morning storm warning
of old scars and fraying skies.February 2024<img alt="You-Are-Not-the-Sunrise.png" src="media/writing/you-are-not-the-sunrise.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2024-you-are-not-the-sunrise.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2024 You Are Not the Sunrise.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:49:53 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/you-are-not-the-sunrise.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/you-are-not-the-sunrise.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024 Norwegian Snow]]></title><description><![CDATA[I mourn for things I will never know -
how a mustache would feel against my lips,
how a walk in the Norwegian snow
would freeze my January fingertips.How a mustache would feel against my lips,
and how the Norway Northern lights
would freeze my January fingertips
before the warmth of heavy quilted nights.Oh how the Norway Northern lights
would open my hungry, empty eyes
before the warmth of heavy quilted nights.
Mustached lips upon my thighswould open my hungry, empty eyes
to a hope in something beyond tomorrow.
Mustached lips upon my thighs -
I mourn for things I will never know.February 4, 2024<img alt="norwegian_snow.jpg" src="media/writing/norwegian_snow.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2024-norwegian-snow.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2024 Norwegian Snow.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:49:27 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/norwegian_snow.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/norwegian_snow.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 Iridescent Sleep]]></title><description><![CDATA[The dreams began with the old woman
tucked in her cryo-chamber,
a botanist from another time altogether.&nbsp;
Dreams of young green tendrils wrapping
around her chilled wrists and ankles while
she slept the iridescent sleep of the edge of galaxies.The dreams spread to the surgeon,
kept at 32 degrees Celsius in the pod next door.
Dreams of his own bronchi shrinking while
his heart beat the time of infancy, his skin
bathed in the luminescence of the bio-scanner,
while he was held in the hearts of love long dead.The dreams finally came to the futurenaut,
the one who mapped light years,
the one who sketched colonies,
the one who slept frozen in his
first shot at immortality.Dreams of ultraviolet light and newborn
stars ripping through his frontal cortex,
replacing objectives with cosmic gas and&nbsp;
colors that shifted at precarious angles.They had arrived at the pillars in the heart
of the nebula, birth place of stars and creation.
7,000 light years from an earth frozen by a spent sun.It was the pillars that brought the dreams of iridescent sleep.
It was the pillars, the creators of stars, that welcomed
her children home and bathed them in colors long dead.April 2, 2023“iridescent_sleep.jpg” could not be found.]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2023-iridescent-sleep.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2023 Iridescent Sleep.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:45:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 Green]]></title><description><![CDATA[You don’t remember
what green means,
fresh and bursting
from snow fed mud.
What first blades
can teach you
after many months
of monochrome grey.You have become unyielding
like dry husks
of milkweed, shedding
silver strands of fall
while you lie dormant
dreaming of monarchs.For you I will paint
nothing but flowers
until color returns
to your face and you
remember how to open
to the sun before
true birth of leaves.I will paint you nothing but flowers
until you remember how to bloom.March 27, 2023<img alt="green_photo.jpg" src="media/writing/green_photo.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2023-green.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2023 Green.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:45:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/green_photo.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/green_photo.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[09.5 Digital Garden Ideas]]></title><description><![CDATA[
finished writings that I don't want to submit or have already been published
writings in progress
thoughts on writing
writing updates rabbit holes that I go down with links and incomplete thoughts
school subjects book logs
current reads lyrics
concerts
playlists digital art
collage
photography quotes
book passages
poetry bits journal
goals
progress
lists
my reclamation journey ideas place for people to add their thoughts to things I put out there
an alternative to social media audio clips? voice notes?
list of other digital gardens/blogs
weekly notes
Square of Roses
Ink &amp; Echo]]></description><link>01-seeds/09.5-digital-garden-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/09.5 Digital Garden Ideas.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:38:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Links]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.letterspace.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.letterspace.org/" target="_self">Robert Van Vliet: Fleeting</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.vianegativa.us/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.vianegativa.us/" target="_self">Via Negativa</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://jasoncrane.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://jasoncrane.org/" target="_self">Jason Crane</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://ellipticalmovements.wordpress.com/category/poetry-2/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://ellipticalmovements.wordpress.com/category/poetry-2/" target="_self">Billy Mills: Elliptical Movements</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://clayandbranches.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://clayandbranches.com/" target="_self">Romana Iorga: Clay and Branches</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://chocolateisaverb.wordpress.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://chocolateisaverb.wordpress.com/" target="_self">J.I. Kleinberg: Chocolate is a Verb</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.drewmyron.com/blog" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.drewmyron.com/blog" target="_self">Drew Myron</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://gooduniversenextdoor.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://gooduniversenextdoor.com/" target="_self">Carolee Bennett: Good Universe Next Door</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://ellyfromearth.wordpress.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://ellyfromearth.wordpress.com/" target="_self">E.E. Nobbs: Elly From Earth</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://creativeramblings.com/blog/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://creativeramblings.com/blog/" target="_self">Cendrine Marrouat: Creative Ramblings</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.timothy-green.org/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.timothy-green.org/" target="_self">Timothy Green</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://robertokaji.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://robertokaji.com/" target="_self">Robert Okaji: O at the Edges</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://kolasch.com/jacob-kolaschs-poetry/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://kolasch.com/jacob-kolaschs-poetry/" target="_self">Jacob Kolasch</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://therumpus.net/sections/blogs/poetry-2/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://therumpus.net/sections/blogs/poetry-2/" target="_self">The Rumpus: Poetry</a>&nbsp;<br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.thelithag.com/poetry" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.thelithag.com/poetry" target="_self">Adele Evershed: The Lit Hag</a><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.nineteendegrees.net/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.nineteendegrees.net/" target="_self">J.G. Orudjev: Nineteen Degrees</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.noelleillustration.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.noelleillustration.com/" target="_self">Noelle Illustration</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.thepigeonletters.com/blogs/1" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.thepigeonletters.com/blogs/1" target="_self">Peggy Dean: The Pigeon Letters</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.lizruest.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.lizruest.com/" target="_self">Liz Ruest</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://leilaandpo.studio/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://leilaandpo.studio/" target="_self">Jennifer Nichols: Leila and Po</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://finaempire.art/digital-art" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://finaempire.art/digital-art" target="_self">Jeff Fina: Fina Empire</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://leslierottnerart.com/portfolio" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://leslierottnerart.com/portfolio" target="_self">Lisa Rottner</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.lululaberlue.com/journaling-gallery" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.lululaberlue.com/journaling-gallery" target="_self">Lulu Laberlue: Happy Journals</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.greetvandam.nl/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.greetvandam.nl/" target="_self">Greet Van Dam</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://katedrewdesigns.com/pages/portfolio" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://katedrewdesigns.com/pages/portfolio" target="_self">Kate Drew Designs</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.tayneetinsley.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.tayneetinsley.com/" target="_self">Taynee Tinsley</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.petra-heidrich.de/galerie/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.petra-heidrich.de/galerie/" target="_self">Petra Heidrich</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://akirakusaka.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://akirakusaka.com/" target="_self">Akira Kusaka</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://allanbealy.blogspot.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://allanbealy.blogspot.com/" target="_self">Allan Bealy</a><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://kelseysmithphotography.net/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://kelseysmithphotography.net/" target="_self">Kelsey Smith</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.alexkittoe.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.alexkittoe.com/" target="_self">Alex Kittoe</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.waywelling.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.waywelling.com/" target="_self">Way Welling</a><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://austinkleon.com/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://austinkleon.com/" target="_self">Austin Kleon</a>]]></description><link>04-rabbit-holes/links.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">04 Rabbit Holes/Links.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:36:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Unfinished Essay ~ Writing Thoughts]]></title><description><![CDATA[ It's all made up. All of the rules and suggestions and even the grammar is all made up. It's designed to make it easy for publishers to publish your work in a way that makes them the most profits. Yes, it also makes for clear communication and that's important when writing an email, a letter, a news story, or an essay, but it's much less important in poetry and fiction. Play with word choice and punctuation and spacing. e.e. cummings, Mark Z. Danielewski's "House of Leaves." They broke the rules and it worked. Sometimes a cliche is what works. It's what everyone understands. There's a reason things become cliche - they're universal. Yes, sometimes we want to find a brand new way of saying things, but sometimes that brand new way is so incomprehensible that no one knows what you're trying to say and then the purpose of writing - to convey something - is lost. Don't get so hung up on worrying about avoiding cliches that you don't write at all. On the other hand, don't worry about being understood or liked by everyone, because that will never happen. Someone will hate what you're doing or misinterpret your meaning. Everyone brings their own lens to reading and will look at everything through that lens. You can't control that. Write for you and your audience will follow. Sometimes there's a feeling or a flow to a poem or a story that transcends the meaning. That's a cool thing too.
I was in a writer's group and the woman leading it had been sexually abused as a child. I felt awful for her that she had lived a life full of abuse. She seemed to put everything through that lens. I wrote a poem that she interpreted as being about a little girl who had been abused. No one else in the group got that from the poem and it was certainly not the story I was telling. Personal experience will influence the reader and there's only so much you can do to control that. You can't let it guide what you write. It's ok to write without the goal of submitting and being published. If that's what you want, awesome! Go for it! If you just want to write and self publish, post to social media, post to a blog, hide it away in a drawer, that's just as valid! You are not less than because you haven't been published by the gatekeepers of words. Some published work is atrocious and some fan fiction is incredibly well written. It's all valid and worth doing.
In that same writer's workshop I mentioned earlier, I came to detest editing and trying to defend the meaning of my poetry. I ]]></description><link>02-seedlings/unfinished-essay-~-writing-thoughts.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">02 Seedlings/Unfinished Essay ~ Writing Thoughts.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:34:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Unfinished Poem ~ Unfinished]]></title><description><![CDATA[I don't write in form
I'm sorry I'm sorry
I can't write in rhyme
I'm sorry I'm sorry
My imagination went with the pills
but I could drive
My muse took to water
but I could eat
I am dry
as winter
I am empty
as your truth]]></description><link>02-seedlings/unfinished-poem-~-unfinished.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">02 Seedlings/Unfinished Poem ~ Unfinished.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:33:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Unfinished Poem ~ Simulation]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the simulation
repetition is necessary
for smooth game playdoppelgängers
prairie
rain forests
unknowable oceansthe repetition is necessary
for smooth game playdeja vu
monotony]]></description><link>02-seedlings/unfinished-poem-~-simulation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">02 Seedlings/Unfinished Poem ~ Simulation.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:32:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Unfinished Poem ~ Contemplations]]></title><description><![CDATA[contemplations on your mouth:your words slip under my tongue
like sublingual morphine
poetic pain killers
for chronic ennui
lips an awakeningcontemplations on your hands:touch like an understandingclear water ecstasy
blessed by Freyacontemplations on your breath]]></description><link>02-seedlings/unfinished-poem-~-contemplations.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">02 Seedlings/Unfinished Poem ~ Contemplations.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:32:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lorraine Hansberry Synthesis]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Maiden, The Mother, The CroneAncient tales tell of the three stages of a woman’s life merged with the archetype of the triple goddess - the maiden, the mother, and the crone. Each stage is further symbolized by a phase of the moon, and what the ancient astrologers thought each of these phases represented. The new moon waxing to full, as a maiden waxes to mother; the full moon waning to a dark crescent, as the mother wanes to crone. A Raisin in the Sun features three women embodying these three stages. Beneatha is the waxing maiden with an idealistic, hopeful view of the future. Ruth is the mother with her life full of the demands of others and very little time to think about her own needs. Lena is the wise, waning matriarch and the old ways of family life. Each of these stages informs the place where these woman make the decisions that will affect the entire Younger family.Because of Lorraine Hansberry’s early death at thirty-four, she never experienced all of the stages of a woman’s life, though she accomplished much in the time she had. Through Beneatha, Ruth, and Lena, she lived all of these milestones on the page and on the stage. Perhaps, with her background in activism, Hansberry was also saying something about the fight for equal rights with each of these stages. Beneatha was the fresh, energized fight for equality, Ruth the disillusioned middle generation who would like to see change, but is so tired of fighting. Lena is the old status quo way of thinking, where women make the best of their lot in life and are submissive to men. The man currently in her life being her son, Walter Lee. While his actions drive the plot of A Raisin in the Sun, it is the relationship and reactions of the three women that really tell the story.Lorraine Hansberry has said that she modeled the character of twenty-year-old Beneatha after herself.&nbsp; A young, radical, feminist woman with big dreams beyond the expected trajectory of a woman’s life in the 1950s. As Hansberry stated in her 1964 speech to the United Negro College Fund creative writing contest winners,“I wanted to be able to come here and speak with you on this occasion because you are young, gifted, and black. … I, for one, can think off no more dynamic combination that a person might be.” (Nemiroff 256) Hansberry could have been talking about Beneatha. Beneatha is the still fresh, idealistic archetype of the maiden represented by the new moon, a time for setting intentions and looking toward the future. She is energy, the discovery of creative potential, and the planting of seeds. In Act I, Lena asks Beneatha, “Why you got to flit so from one thing to another, baby?” Beneatha then replies, “I don’t flit! I—I experiment with different forms of expression—.” (Hansberry, A Raisin in the Sun 50)Beneatha has a dream to be a doctor and heal the world, and she has not yet been required to modify or give up those dreams. Beneatha has not yet had to shoulder the duties and expectations of the older Younger women, and while the true fight for equality wouldn’t happen for another decade, she enjoys opportunity not afforded to Ruth and Lena when they were her age. Beneatha feels free to express her atheistic views in the naive way of a younger generation who believes their opinions will be shared with everyone. Lena slaps her for disrespecting God in Lena’s home. After this exchange, Ruth says to Beneatha, “You think you a woman, Bennie—but you still a little girl. What you did was childish—so you got treated like a child.” (Hansberry, A Raisin in the Sun 54) This is how the maiden can be viewed by the mother and the crone, as someone to be corrected rather than respected.Hansberry said, in her 1959 keynote speech at the First Conference of Negro Writers, “I have come to maturity, as we all must, knowing that greed and malice and indifference to human misery, bigotry and corruption, brutality and, perhaps above all else, ignorance abound in this world.” (Hansberry, The Negro Writer and His Roots 11) Surely Ruth Younger has seen plenty in her thirty-two years of life to be exhausted by the indifference of the world to her suffering. In much of the play, Ruth is a mothering presence for everyone. She wakes Walter up for work, makes him get up on time, gets everyone in and out of the bathroom in an organized way, and makes sure everyone is fed before they leave the house. This mothering phase of a woman’s life, and the corresponding symbolism of the full moon, is when women are said to be at their busiest. It is a time to reap the harvest of the seeds sown in the maiden phase of life, to realize a woman’s full potential, to accept responsibility, and to practice selfless compassion.Ruth does not take her mothering lightly as is shown in all of the ways she desires a better life for Travis. While she has put a down payment on an abortion, it isn’t because she doesn’t want this new baby. It’s because she sees all the ways the family she already has will suffer and the mother in her wants to protect them all. Lena tells Walter, “When the world gets ugly enough—a woman will do anything for her family. The part that’s already living.” (Hansberry, A Raisin in the Sun 77) Ruth has moved beyond the idealistic, carefree years of youth and into the depths of life. A life crowded with work, household duties, children, the realities of society, and a settled, but somewhat troubled marriage. Her dream is a better life for Travis, and to take some of the tension off of Walter so they can enjoy their marriage again. She has been informed by three decades of living that have worn her down, but in the scene after Walter has invested the family’s money and her marriage is enjoying a rejuvenation, it is clear how much life and passion remain in this vital phase of Ruth’s life.Hansberry didn’t get to reach the crone stage of life, although she said, “I wish to live because life has within it that which is good, that which is beautiful, and that which is love. Therefore, since I have known all of these things, I have found them to be reason enough and — I wish to live. Moreover, because this is so, I wish others to live for generations and generations and generations and generations.” (Hansberry, The Negro Writer and His Roots 11) Through the play’s matriarch, Lena, Hansberry lived for generations. Lena is the matriarch who demands the respect she has earned after a life of sacrifice. There is a belief that “older women hold the energy of the menstrual blood within their bodies and make internal wisdom instead of external children” (Pinkola Estés 504), Lena is this wise crone.Lena’s life stage is further symbolized by the Younger’s apartment. Once the rugs, furniture, and walls were new and spotless, now time has worn them both old and tired. Yet, like the apartment, Lena is sill a home and a strength for her family. She is the strong backed matriarch who demands the respect of her children, and the soft hearted grandmother who allows them their failures. The crone stage is symbolized by the waning moon, a time for release. In Act II, Lena decides it’s time for her to let go of her place as the head of the family and pass it on to Walter. She is ready to put her faith in the next generation. “I want you to take this money and take three thousand dollars and put it in a savings account for Beneatha's medical schooling. The rest you put in a checking account—with your name on it. And from now on any penny that come out of it or that go in it is for you to look after. For you to decide. It ain’t much, but it’s all I got in the world and I’m putting it in your hands. I’m telling you to be the head of this family from now on like you supposed to be.” (Hansberry, A Raisin in the Sun 107) Her only dream is a little garden with enough sunshine to grow some flowers, and a home for her family.Throughout A Raisin in the Sun, the Younger women are met with challenges to the family, to their dreams, and to their small sense of security, especially through the actions of Walter Lee. Their different ways of dealing with their struggles are most pronounced in Act III when they discover Walter has lost all of the money they had left for Beneatha’s schooling and for the family’s future. In this act we can almost see Beneatha cross a threshold from naive maiden to informed woman. In the scene with Asagai, Beneatha is mourning the loss of her dream, the loss of her medical school money through events outside of her control. She’s ready to give up on school, on being a doctor, on saving the world, until Asagai asks her if she had earned the money. Had that money truly been hers to lose? “Then isn’t there something wrong in a house—in a world—where all dreams, good or bad, must depend on the death of a man?” (Hansberry, A Raisin in the Sun 134) Beneatha is furious, as she should be, at Walter. She is ready to forsake him as her brother, yet the burgeoning woman in her sees the truth of this statement.Ruth, on the other hand, is ready to look past this incident as long as she can still achieve her dream of getting the family out of the ghetto. When Lena decides that they aren’t moving now that the money is gone, Ruth becomes desperate and promises to clean all the houses and wash all the sheets in America if she has to. Lena, who has already seen so much misery and sacrifice, is willing to tell herself that her dream was just too big. “Lord, ever since I was a little girl, I always remembers people saying, ‘Lena—Lena Eggleston, you aims too high all the time. You needs to slow down and see life a little more like it is. Just slow down some.’ That's what they always used to say down home.” (Hansberry, A Raisin in the Sun 139) Lena has decided that her due has finally come. That she needs to give her dreams a rest. She tells Beneatha that now is the time to love Walter. Now is the time for forgiveness. Now is the time for release of all the anger they have felt towards Walter. From anger, to desperation, to resolve, each woman’s reaction is somewhat dependent on their stage of life and the experiences that have had.Beneatha, the maiden, the energetic new moon. Ruth, the mother, the surrendering full moon, and Lena, the waxing crescent due her rest and release from worry. Menstruation, birth, and the ceasing of the reproductive years, and the moon symbolism that has come to represent each of these phases, can be a very powerful force in the lives of women. Each stage brings challenges, experiences, and subtle shifts in energy and relationships. Informing how a woman problem solves, how she dreams, and how she loves. Lorraine Hansberry gives them all a voice in A Raisin in the Sun, and through her they come to life and truly tell the story of all of humanity.Works CitedAmerican Playhouse, “Raisin In The Sun (1989).” YouTube, uploaded by Reelblack One, 13November 2019, <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jzfgwxENvLk" target="_self">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jzfgwxENvLk</a>Hansberry, Lorraine A Raisin in the Sun, Vintage Books, 1994Hansberry, Lorraine, “The Negro Writer and His Roots, The Black Scholar, vol. 12, no. 2, 1981,pp. 2-12Louisiana Public Broadcasting, “Lorraine Hansberry: Sighted Eyes / Feeling Heart | AmericanMasters | Panel Discussion”, YouTube, 22 March 2018,<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GL6i1JBl9ps" target="_self">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GL6i1JBl9ps</a>Nemiroff, Robert, To Be Young, Gifted, and Black, Prentice Hall, 1969Pinkola Estés, Clarissa Women Who Run With the Wolves, Random House, 1992Savage, Linda E., “The Three Phases of a Woman’s Life”, Therapists of San Diego,<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.sandiegotherapists.com/threestages.html" target="_self">https://www.sandiegotherapists.com/threestages.html</a>, Accessed 12 October 2023“The-Maiden-The-Mother-The-Crone.png” could not be found.]]></description><link>03-flowers/essays/lorraine-hansberry-synthesis.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/essays/Lorraine Hansberry Synthesis.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:03:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Clearing the Creative River]]></title><description><![CDATA[When did this obsession with social media take hold? Was it when my dad got Prodigy in the late 80s and I was suddenly connected to people via message boards? I made connections there I don't think my still analog brain understood to be different from real life. Through the years I had various blogs, participated in various message boards - sharing every detail of my life with strangers who I thought were friends, but now can't even remember their names. I was part of a digital scrapbooking community where I posted my kid's pictures and every detail of their childhoods. Nothing was sacred because the sharing felt intimate, like I was among friends.Enter Facebook. Now I WAS among friends! My need to share was supercharged. Surely these people were like me, knew me, agreed with me on every aspect of life! Wait... what? My cousin is racist? My uncle is a homophobe? Suddenly everything I thought I knew was tilted. And there was so much to take in and sort through and try to make sense of. Saved posts, watch later youtube lists, read it later apps full of varied, dense information that no brain is equipped to contain. Twitter, Instagram, more blogs, more ways to show the world that I'm here too and look at all the things I can do! Look at all the thoughts I have!Until there is no thought that doesn't get formatted into 280 characters. Will it fit in an Instagram caption? No one will read it if it's too long. Condense, shorten, shrink, twist into something palatable. Every word carefully chosen to impress - who? Thousands of strangers who only hope you'll follow them if they drop a like or a comment? Now it's not enough to create for the masses because I don't even know if the masses are bots. My brain is still living on 80s message boards full of the few people who had heard of Prodigy when the world has moved on to bot farms and buying likes.Yet, there is still the dopamine release from scrolling a feed and seeing people I "know." There is still an illusion of connection and community. A brain that sees these faces as friends when they are complete strangers. (1/3)Until it starts to feel hollow. Until it starts to feel one sided and completely empty. Until there is the realization that no one really cares, they only want to be noticed too.For awhile I kept twisting myself to fit whatever would feed the algorithm, or make people like me again. For awhile I thought that sharing everything was the way to connect. Then, a stray comment read here, a thread read there - all causing me to hesitate or abandon completely anything that brings me joy because someone else said it's lacking. Said it's not real art, not real poetry, not real enough for a virtual world. They're right, just not in the way they think they are. It's not fake because they have put some sort of expectation on content creation, it's fake because it's content creation and not just creating.Here is where I find myself. 34 years into exposing myself to various outlets to try to find some kind of connection in a disconnected world. Feeling guilt when I don't share my feelings on every world happening, shame when I stay silent because I am empty. Still mining the old for something to feed the machine, since the well of creation has long run dry.Messages appear when we are ready to see them and I have had three in the last month that have made me reflect:i. In group therapy, the therapist asked, "If your 80 year old self came and sat down across from you and told you what she wished you had worried less about in your life, what would those things be?" My first thought was social media. She would sit down across from me and say, "Why did you give up so much of yourself to the ether? Why did you not hold something back for yourself? Why did you let strangers tell you how to be and how to make? Why?" I had no answer. Only the deep realization that she was right and that hopefully it wasn't too late. (2/3)ii. I read closely Women Who Run With the Wolves for my women's literature class. Among the very flowery prose and woo-woo Jungian psychoanalysis, there was a real message that spoke to me. Women have been taught by culture to make ourselves small, silence ourselves, and to let our inner instinctual voice be silenced. We have lost the ways of our matriarchal lineage and all of our stories have been hijacked by men and watered down. Crones made into witches, goddess religions into heresy. In the process women have been made to become dutiful, well behaved creatures who suffer from depression, anxiety, and ennui without quite knowing why. Our creative flow is disrupted by the voices in our heads telling us that we will be shunned or judged if we write that or sculpt this. Our creative rivers have been turned to sludge. Social media plays right into this by telling us what will please the algorithm or the platform (created by men) and we once again give our creativity and minds over to something designed to make us perfect homemakers, curators of the male gaze, and aesthetic influencers. I no longer want to create in this culture of popularity contests. I need to turn from the public eye.iii. My 3rd point will seem a bit hypocritical after what I've just said, but it was a comment I read on Notes, the Twitter-like part of Substack. How would the classic artists have created differently if they had to have a social media presence to be creatives who were noticed? Would they have played it safe and not developed their own style? The comment asked the question of whether art is about validation or valuation. Do I want to be validated by the masses for what I create or do I want to create something that has lasting value for myself? I choose the latter.I have come to disdain the need to create a brand, an aesthetic, to even fit into a genre. I hope artists start stretching their limbs and trying new things. I hope they never stop growing.I've decided to stop creating in public for awhile. To stop posting anything art related whether that be collage or writing. I don't plan to leave social media altogether, just change the way I interact with it. I want to begin to create in private, in solitude, in a cave of my own making. I don't want to think about social media so much. I have no plan for the future where all of this is concerned. I'm not putting a time limit on it. I'm simply sitting with the feeling that for now I'm ok not creating at all or creating for my eyes only. This is very removed from the past reasons when I would step back from socials. This is not because I am running away from myself or cringing at what I've made. It's not because I want to escape. It's because I want to run to myself. I want to value what I make. I want to hear my own voice again.I've privated my Instagram account and it may become more of a place where I just ramble or share my personal stuff. I don't have a plan. I do want to stay connected to the people I have come to love. Not just imaginary connections giving me shots of dopamine, but the real ones who I care deeply about. Our journeys have crossed paths for too long to go it alone now. November 23, 2023<img alt="Copy of Copy of K.png" src="media/writing/copy-of-copy-of-k.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-flowers/essays/clearing-the-creative-river.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/essays/Clearing the Creative River.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:02:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[A ramble about books that nobody asked for]]></title><description><![CDATA[In my teens I read books I enjoyed. Books not recommended by any list. Books that were in no way literary masterpieces. Silly teen romances or light horror, fantasy, sci-fi. Whatever looked like something I would enjoy.In my twenties I read chick lit, crime fiction, true crime, and whatever struck my fancy. I loved celebrity autobiographies, especially of rock stars.Then at some point I decided that I needed to move away from Bridget Jones's Diary and Motley Crue's The Dirt and get more serious about reading. Start reading well respected literary fiction or books from the 1800s (Pride and Prejudice 🤮) or sciencey non-fiction. I read a lot of books I enjoyed, but I struggled through many I didn't because I thought I should.(I did go through a period about ten years ago where I read nothing but zombie books. I'm not sure what that was all about.)In the last few years I have found myself not reading as much. Choosing books because they are what I feel I "should" be reading. Lots of non-fiction. Lots of commentary on society. I haven't enjoyed reading as much, although again, I've read some really excellent books. I'm sure I've learned a lot, but there were so many books I just didn't even finish.Then this month I read this:
(One to Watch)Kinda chick lit/romance but with a protagonist who isn't silly or clumsy or needy. Grown up chick lit. I loved it! I read Resonance which you know I loved. And now I'm reading this:(Boyfriend Material)Definitely not an Oprah (maybe it's Reese Witherspoon doing the recommending now?) pick or a sciencey non-fiction, but it is so much fun and I'm rediscovering why I love reading.I think there's room for the non-fiction that interests you and for the classics, but there's also room for the cozy murder mysteries and the rom-com romps too.We need to quit being so snobby about books and music and enjoy them as they were meant to be enjoyed. Tofu and kale are great, but sometimes you need some Doritos or chocolate. If we've learned anything in the last year it's that life can be too fucking short. Read the damn romance, listen to some Harry Styles, and eat the ice cream. You'll be happier for it.September 2022]]></description><link>03-flowers/essays/a-ramble-about-books-that-nobody-asked-for.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/essays/A ramble about books that nobody asked for.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:02:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ideas Many of Us Hold that I Invite you to Challenge]]></title><description><![CDATA[ Your writing/art is too basic, immature, pedestrian You are not a real artist No one cares or will see what you create What is the point of art? Don’t you have better ways to spend your time? You write/create the same thing over and over Everyone is going to laugh at you Anyone who says they like your art is lying, humoring you, or just being nice You are not special/cool enough to be a part of this You/your art is not special, unique or worth it Whatever you do don’t write about THAT risque, dark, personal thing Keep yourself, your body, your feelings hidden Don’t talk, share, or feel too much You are not talented, pretty, smart, popular, trendy, thin, whatever enough to succeed You are too old/young. No one wants to hear what such a boring person has to say. Here is my response to most of those statements: If you are enjoying what you are doing, are not neglecting the people you need to care for or your own needs, are not hurting anyone (including yourself), then creativity purely for the sake of producing something that wasn’t there before is a more than worthy way to spend your time. Maybe it won’t make money. Taking time away from capitalist pursuits is good for the soul. Maybe it won’t change the world. We all need time to recharge by pursuing something that has no point other than making us (and maybe others) happy. No matter who you are there is an audience for you. There are other people living a similar existence who are grateful to find art they can relate to. You can never be too old or young to create. It’s not like being an olympic athlete or driving a car. There is no age limit and there is no prerequisite of having a certain level of talent or experience. All you need is the desire to create.&nbsp; If you create something bad, who cares? No one was hurt. No wars were started. If someone laughs at you because you had the desire to create, had fun doing it, and put it out into the world - those people need to spend more time creating something of their own and less time being assholes. Maybe you’re not unique. Or special. Maybe it’s all been done before. Maybe someone will think it’s garbage. It doesn’t matter because it’s about the act of creating and not about what happens once it’s released to the world. People may choose not to follow you. They may even block you. That just means that your art isn’t for them. Plenty more might decide you are just what they were looking for. You are enough. You are worthy of creating the thing that lives in your heart. There really are no rules. We have made up rules, but they are not real. You can do it any way you please. Fuck the critics and the people who say you’re not doing it “right.” Dare to break their rules because that’s the only way art will ever advance. It is really ok to use your time to make shit. You don’t have to justify it or understand why you want to make shit or explain to the world what your shit is about. You just have to go where your heart leads you. That’s the only way to be happy. Let the rest go. November 11, 2021“IMG_0291.jpg” could not be found.]]></description><link>03-flowers/essays/ideas-many-of-us-hold-that-i-invite-you-to-challenge.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/essays/Ideas Many of Us Hold that I Invite you to Challenge.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:01:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Women I Admire]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Michelle Obama
Cyndi Lauper
Jamie Lee Curtis
Mary Tyler Moore
Jane Goodall
AOC
RBG
]]></description><link>00-kelli-anna/women-i-admire.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">00 Kelli Anna/Women I Admire.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:00:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What Feeds Me]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Fall Out Boy
reading mysteries
sci-fi
romance
horror My Chemical Romance
my weekly/daily newsletters
Patrick Stump
poetry
social media
spending time with my daughters
my friends
daydreaming
talking
bookstores
writing
music pop
pop punk
punk
alternative sunsets
my cats
time at home
concerts
]]></description><link>00-kelli-anna/what-feeds-me.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">00 Kelli Anna/What Feeds Me.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 13:59:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[I Love]]></title><description><![CDATA[ { an ever evolving list } … writing poems no one will read … cookies dipped in coffee 🍪 … hotel lobby breakfasts … My Chemical Romance … going out for breakfast … libraries and bookstores 📖 … stationary and office supplies … Star Wars ... flowers 🌷 ... Fall Out Boy ... concerts ... cute little mushrooms 🍄 ]]></description><link>00-kelli-anna/i-love.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">00 Kelli Anna/I Love.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 13:59:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[headphones]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/headphones.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/headphones.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/headphones.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 14:56:44 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/headphones.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/headphones.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[09 Blog & Online Ideas]]></title><description><![CDATA[
loving this week
from my notebooks
confessional
week in reading
week in objects (photos)
poetry? collage? flowers?galleries
collage
seasons
Textures
Flowers
Sky
Cities
NatureSmashwords
Pillowfort
ghost]]></description><link>01-seeds/09-blog-&amp;-online-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/09 Blog &amp; Online Ideas.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 14:40:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[vignette]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/vignette.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/vignette.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/vignette.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 14:36:34 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/vignette.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/vignette.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hopeful Youth, Old Despair]]></title><description><![CDATA[Remember how it felt to believe in what you feel? When in our youth we held our emotions on the fabric of our sleeve and felt as if we had discovered sadness and anger. When we looked at the world as if it was ours and just knew that we could be the ones to change it. How we thought we’d live on mars and drive a flying car and come back to reunions as rock stars in skinny slinky dresses with a movie star on our arm.Remember when we believed in all of the feelings we felt before people started telling us that feeling them was wrong? When they started telling us we were naive or emo and how you can’t cry at work or in front of people. How life isn't fair, so don't demand more. How no one was going to save the world after all so take your desk job and your pay check and go home and watch tv.&nbsp;We lost something along the way when we stopped believing in love and utopia. When we let our fear be the place from where we drove our heart. We were all those kids standing up for change. We were once those loud voices yelling for a better world. We were all ready to feed the poor and give voice to the downtrodden, until we became the downtrodden, or forgot the poor, or lost our voice.Change never seems to stick and the same problems that confront us now are just a new shape to all of the things that have always vexxed the world.Sometimes we stumble onto old words that fit the current situation exactly and we are amazed that someone from so long ago knew just how things would turn out. Knew just how we’re feeling now and we wonder if they were psychic, but the real reason they knew is that nothing has changed. We are the same cavemen protecting our clan from outsiders and feeding our bodies hunks of meat. We are fighting the same wars against different people. We are arguing the same points with different words. We are still barely getting by and dying and falling hard into despair.I can’t give anyone hope. I can’t bring anyone change. I was the hopeful youth in torn jeans and fresh skin. I was the hope of tomorrow.&nbsp;Now I'm nihilism in midsection fat, gray hair hopelessness.And the youth buried deep in me despises me.Now I’m everything I was fighting against. Suburban mom, 2 kids, 2 cars, 2 much, 2 fat… I'm what the hopeful future never thinks they will be. And the hopeful youth buried deep in me despises it.March 26, 2018]]></description><link>03-flowers/essays/hopeful-youth,-old-despair.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/essays/Hopeful Youth, Old Despair.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 15:59:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[20231006_eclipse_of_epiphanies]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/art/20231006_eclipse_of_epiphanies.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/art/20231006_eclipse_of_epiphanies.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/art/20231006_eclipse_of_epiphanies.jpg</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 15:14:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/art/20231006_eclipse_of_epiphanies.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/art/20231006_eclipse_of_epiphanies.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 Autumn is a Rusty Birdcage]]></title><description><![CDATA[If flannel was pink could
it ward off a rainstorm?
If green slept in your eyes would
you wake to new growth?
If blue was a watering can would it
finally quench your thirst for the sky?Autumn is a birdcage of rusty iron
trapping us between fire
and ice, a resting place of
amber and gold. A sunrise
of shadows thrown like
bars over our songs.
I listened once and knew you,
before the chill took you home.The cicada song stutters in grey green
like rattlesnake tails on branches
of early autumn oceans.
We are statues before the bees.
Nothing to offer of sweetness.
Only skin and blood and a way
of killing everything beautiful.
We cage the birdsong and
wonder why it doesn’t sound as free.October 5, 2023<img alt="amberandgold.png" src="media/writing/amberandgold.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2023-autumn-is-a-rusty-birdcage.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2023 Autumn is a Rusty Birdcage.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 15:09:31 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/amberandgold.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/amberandgold.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[amberandgold]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/amberandgold.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/amberandgold.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/amberandgold.png</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 15:09:11 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/amberandgold.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/amberandgold.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024 Bindings]]></title><description><![CDATA[I'm still tied in your old knots.
All of you. All of your ties.
Soft velvet cracked old leather. { they chafe just the same }Ghost bindings made of words
and indifference. Young mouths
with mature plans young hands
building sandcastles in folded time.I am bound to old concrete
shadows of form, drained by ghost
teeth and old mouths
dripping red promises.Always sweet tongued
until the bleeding starts.February 2, 2024<img alt="Bindings-2.png" src="media/writing/bindings-2.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2024-bindings.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2024 Bindings.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:55:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/bindings-2.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/bindings-2.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bindings-2]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/bindings-2.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/bindings-2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/Bindings-2.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:55:46 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/bindings-2.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/bindings-2.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[norwegian_snow]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/norwegian_snow.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/norwegian_snow.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/norwegian_snow.jpg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:15:24 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/norwegian_snow.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/norwegian_snow.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[You-Are-Not-the-Sunrise]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/you-are-not-the-sunrise.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/you-are-not-the-sunrise.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/You-Are-Not-the-Sunrise.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:14:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/you-are-not-the-sunrise.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/you-are-not-the-sunrise.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 Insubstantial]]></title><description><![CDATA[We are insubstantial
like the legs of waterbirds
holding the weight
of our own hollow bones
and micro-plastic blood.on the edge of flighton the edge of extinctionBelieving in our solidity,
existing as a reflection
in a ripple of cold water.April 5, 2023<img alt="insubstantial.jpg" src="media/writing/insubstantial.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2023-insubstantial.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2023 Insubstantial.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:01:46 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/insubstantial.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/insubstantial.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[insubstantial]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/insubstantial.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/insubstantial.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/insubstantial.jpg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:01:41 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/insubstantial.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/insubstantial.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[iridescent_sleep 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/iridescent_sleep-2.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/iridescent_sleep-2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/iridescent_sleep 2.jpg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:01:32 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[green_photo]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/green_photo.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/green_photo.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/green_photo.jpg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:00:47 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/green_photo.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/green_photo.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Copy of Copy of K]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/copy-of-copy-of-k.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/copy-of-copy-of-k.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/Copy of Copy of K.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 03:56:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bottled Up Wishes]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/bottled-up-wishes.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/bottled-up-wishes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/Bottled Up Wishes.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 02:58:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[We Are Made of Endings]]></title><description><![CDATA[I dreamt of endings. Frayed strands of yarn, a dead end road, storm clouds rolling out and giving way to blue, the check arriving on a scarred table in a pub at the end of the world. Every night the dreams began at the end and only faded to black like the last scene of an old film. I spent my daylight hours trying to recreate the scene that had come before, but there was nothing. No hint of a remembered dream pulling at the edges of my mind. Just the ending.Then one morning there was only the last bite of a muffin left in the box. The next day only the last sip of cold coffee left in the cup freshly poured. The following afternoon there was only the wrap up of a meeting. The next evening only the last mile to drive home. I spent my nighttime hours trying to recreate the scenes that must have come before, but there was nothing. No hint of a remembered life pulling at the edges of my mind. Only endings.A visit to my doctor, a referral to a neurologist, the last few minutes of a consultation, the table leaving the MRI scanner with no memory of going in. The assurance that everything was fine as the doctor left the room. Getting up from a chair in the psychiatrist’s office with an appointment for another session next week, maybe you have some unremembered trauma, we’ll discuss it more next time. this session was very enlightening. I was only left more in the dark. What had I said? What had I told this stern looking woman with the wire frames and fountain pen? I couldn’t remember walking in the office let alone the words that had left my mouth. Only the ending.Weeks continued on the same way. Dreams of last breaths, falling leaves, the sputtering of a wick in a pool of wax, orgasm without touch, so many backs as people walked away. Days spent consuming last gulps of coffee, last bites of food, the last chapter of every novel. Meetings wrapping up, arriving home without the drive, stepping out of the shower dripping wet without stepping in, hanging up the phone without remembering who I had been talking to. Back to the neurologist, “are you sure? are you sure there isn’t something there? look again.” Back to the psychiatrist, “it’s all slipping away. make it stay. make me more than a last moment. i am only an ending.”Finally opening my eyes to a sterile room in a white gown with tiny faded green dots, just as the light from the setting sun was hitting the dresser on the far side of the room, illuminating the vase of wilting flowers and a water glass with one final sip. I didn’t rise. I didn’t question how this had all happened. It was just another ending.I had often missed the first buds in the spring, a storm rolling in on a sunny day, my heart skipping a beat when I opened the door for a first date. I hadn’t savored being handed the menu to choose, reaching out to take a cup of coffee, fresh and steaming, lighting an unburned wick, turning to the title page of an unread book, letting my hands wander over a body I knew would soon be wrapped around my own. I had seldom thought, “this is the beginning. this moment is where it all starts.” I was made of forgotten beginnings.But the endings, when I was satiated, sad, shattered, thrilled, lost, content… alone, then I knew. Then I stopped to remember that there was a beginning to this ending. There was a spot where I decided I was all in, without the realization that life is just endings, as spring is just the end of winter. As I lay in the ultimate end, alone without even the memory of arriving in this place, I could only feel joy for the reminder that my life had been full of beginnings I never took the time to see. That the way the light was fading in the room was really just the start of the last night. Only the beginning.The beginning of the last night when it all became clear. When I walked out of the sterile room and saw every person who passed me as the joining of ovum and sperm, spinning strands of DNA, an atom of carbon. The hallway darkened to a single point of light in the distance of a cavernous emptiness. The faded dots of my gown floated into the darkness like fireflies to guide my body shed of clothing and worries.I followed as I dissolved into cells, into elements, into galaxies. I spun through the darkness with eight billion other swirling clouds of hydrogen and helium, light and heat, heavy with potential. We had been destroyers. We had been the riders of the apocalypse leaving destruction in our wake. The fellers of trees, the bullets through flesh, the plastic suspended in salt water, the cement over bones. We had been eight billion little endings. Eight billion little endings swirling into one cloud, one singular point of light, one spot blinking in a universe of unnamed black. A heavy mass of souls in a tiny singularity. Waiting. Just another beginning.{ Published in the 2023 Edition of the Elgin Community College Spire Literary Magazine}<img alt="stardust.jpeg" src="media/writing/stardust.jpeg" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-flowers/short-stories/we-are-made-of-endings.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/short stories/We Are Made of Endings.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 02:57:25 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/stardust.jpeg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/stardust.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[stardust]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/stardust.jpeg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/stardust.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/stardust.jpeg</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 02:57:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/stardust.jpeg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/stardust.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Copy of Copy of Copy of Wordmark Substack-8]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/copy-of-copy-of-copy-of-wordmark-substack-8.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/copy-of-copy-of-copy-of-wordmark-substack-8.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/Copy of Copy of Copy of Wordmark Substack-8.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 02:50:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Between Your Lines]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/between-your-lines.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/between-your-lines.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/Between Your Lines.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 02:24:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[marble_gardens]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/writing/marble_gardens.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/writing/marble_gardens.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/writing/marble_gardens.jpg</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 01:15:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/marble_gardens.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/marble_gardens.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[20230331_beautiful_things]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/art/20230331_beautiful_things.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/art/20230331_beautiful_things.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/art/20230331_beautiful_things.JPG</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1980 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/art/20230331_beautiful_things.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/art/20230331_beautiful_things.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[20230525_everything_dies]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="media/art/20230525_everything_dies.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>media/art/20230525_everything_dies.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">media/art/20230525_everything_dies.JPG</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1980 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/art/20230525_everything_dies.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/art/20230525_everything_dies.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 04 02 Iridescent Sleep]]></title><description><![CDATA[The dreams began with the old woman
tucked in her cryo-chamber,
a botanist from another time altogether.&nbsp;
Dreams of young green tendrils wrapping
around her chilled wrists and ankles while
she slept the iridescent sleep of the edge of galaxies.The dreams spread to the surgeon,
kept at 32 degrees Celsius in the pod next door.
Dreams of his own bronchi shrinking while
his heart beat the time of infancy, his skin
bathed in the luminescence of the bio-scanner,
while he was held in the hearts of love long dead.The dreams finally came to the futurenaut,
the one who mapped light years,
the one who sketched colonies,
the one who slept frozen in his
first shot at immortality.Dreams of ultraviolet light and newborn
stars ripping through his frontal cortex,
replacing objectives with cosmic gas and&nbsp;
colors that shifted at precarious angles.They had arrived at the pillars in the heart
of the nebula, birth place of stars and creation.
7,000 light years from an earth frozen by a spent sun.It was the pillars that brought the dreams of iridescent sleep.
It was the pillars, the creators of stars, that welcomed
her children home and bathed them in colors long dead.April 2, 2023“iridescent_sleep.jpg” could not be found.]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2023-04-02-iridescent-sleep.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2023 04 02 Iridescent Sleep.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 14:28:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01.1 Seeds]]></title><link>01-seeds/01.1-seeds.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">01 Seeds/01.1 Seeds.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:49:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024 02 04 Norwegian Snow]]></title><description><![CDATA[I mourn for things I will never know -
how a mustache would feel against my lips,
how a walk in the Norwegian snow
would freeze my January fingertips.How a mustache would feel against my lips,
and how the Norway Northern lights
would freeze my January fingertips
before the warmth of heavy quilted nights.Oh how the Norway Northern lights
would open my hungry, empty eyes
before the warmth of heavy quilted nights.
Mustached lips upon my thighswould open my hungry, empty eyes
to a hope in something beyond tomorrow.
Mustached lips upon my thighs -
I mourn for things I will never know.“norwegian_snow.jpg” could not be found.]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2024-02-04-norwegian-snow.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2024 02 04 Norwegian Snow.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 14:34:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 10 05 Autumn is a Rusty Birdcage]]></title><description><![CDATA[If flannel was pink could
it ward off a rainstorm?
If green slept in your eyes would
you wake to new growth?
If blue was a watering can would it
finally quench your thirst for the sky?Autumn is a birdcage of rusty iron
trapping us between fire
and ice, a resting place of
amber and gold. A sunrise
of shadows thrown like
bars over our songs.
I listened once and knew you,
before the chill took you home.The cicada song stutters in grey green
like rattlesnake tails on branches
of early autumn oceans.
We are statues before the bees.
Nothing to offer of sweetness.
Only skin and blood and a way
of killing everything beautiful.
We cage the birdsong and
wonder why it doesn’t sound as free.October 5, 2023“amberandgold.png” could not be found.]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2023-10-05-autumn-is-a-rusty-birdcage.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2023 10 05 Autumn is a Rusty Birdcage.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 15:09:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2022 11 27 Ink Stains]]></title><description><![CDATA[“Copy of Copy of Copy of Wordmark Substack-8.png” could not be found.It was the way everything was ending. The way everything was over before I could fully appreciate the beauty of it all. The lights, the stage, the audience, the way they hung on every word. Over. Time to return to the underlying hum of the everyday.I stood in the hotel room for the last time. The weeks and months spinning around me like the color of old paper and I breathed in every dust mote. I tried to grasp every emotion that had made me want to write and share in the first place. I had written a novel. I had written a novel that people wanted to read. I had written a novel that people wanted to read and I taken it on a tour. And people had come to listen as I gave voice to my own words. They had stepped up to tables with the book cradled to their chest like a precious memory and I had listened as they gave my words a new voice. Listened as they told me how the story had moved them to tears. How it had settled into their bones and inspired them to make something of their own. To create something with their hands. To put their own piece of something out to the world. I had hugged them, held their hands, wiped away tears, watched their eyes light up when they talked about their own art. I had seen their art for myself. Carried carefully in folders and notebooks and read from screens. And I had cheered on every one. From the shockingly bad to the earth shattering good. Each one was a masterpiece and an homage to my own work, which I had only dreamed would light a spark when I was alone in a dark room with only the words to guide me.Weeks and months, tables and rooms, stages and hotels, and now... quiet. There had been friendship. Seven authors on one tour of book conventions across the country, across the globe. Seven people with different stories and styles and reasons for putting their words in order. Seven friends. Some better, some worse, but all becoming something to each other in the months of travel, exhaustion, elation and wonder. What now? Would these new friendships carry into the everyday? Would they survive the heartbreak and joy and breakfast and writer’s block of the day to day? Living on separate coasts, separate continents?Survive the introverted, focused life of a writer all alone at a keyboard playing out the lives of people having much more exciting existences than the writers themselves? Typing all of the things they could never be or say onto a little screen in a little room in a little life? For months these seven strangers had been someone else. We had lived the lives we had only dared to write about. And now... would there be enough to hold us together?I thought about all of this as I stood in a white room full of white furniture. White flowers on the white tabletop. I was a bruise of black clothing in this perfect room. I was a bruise of black moods in my other life. Every pure thing that came along was left stained by the sadness I wore like rainwater on my skin. The fact that I had managed to write a book that made people better instead of sad was nothing short of a miracle. My life was empty and black and the only place I felt I fit was in that small dark room in front of that screen writing about people who were infinitely happier than I was. I was an imposter on this book tour. I had laughed with the others and listened to their fears. I had leant a shoulder for tears and I had somehow, I still have no idea how, held onto my own. For once I hadn’t been the sad girl. I had been the inspiration. I had been the happy. I had been the joy. I had felt the joy. Away from everything familiar that made me feel like darkness, like night moving in, like a black spot in a white room. Which one was real? The person I had always been or the one I had become in a few short months? Who would I meet when I got back home? Who would the few remaining people see?What had he seen? Late nights when we sat in each other’s space, among the things that only meant something to us. Me in his room among the ink and color and storyboards. Listening to his soul pour from the speakers when he played the music that pushed him to draw his stories. Among his holy sweaters and ill fitting t-shirts. What had he seen? When he came to my room, a bottle in hand, a sheepish grin, a shrug when I mentioned our early morning. When he sat among my fresh book purchases, when he listened to the sadness pouring from my speakers. When he looked right at me and I was sure he saw the darkness and didn’t care, maybe even found comfort there. What had he seen? Did it matter now that it was over? Tomorrow we all boarded our own flights to be scattered to the winds, and this would only live inus as a remember when.I didn’t even know if he saw anything other than a kindred spirit in an awkward situation. The other five were real humans. Real people who could discuss stocks and interest rates and where they were vacationing next summer with their real life families. With their real life friends. They were solid and alive. But he was more fluid, more hazy, more ghostlike, more like the darkness that drifted into my brain when I was alone with my words for too long. Was I just a drinking buddy distraction for nights he’d had enough of the solid people? Was I the only one who felt there might be more? Would I board my plane tomorrow and someday write an ending that sold a book but left me empty?Back to the white room, to the bright day, to the glare of tomorrow shining in the window that dominated the room and brought the strange city right to my feet. A view that brought me right to my knees. How could I go back to my tiny life, alone with the darkness? Maybe I could just keep boarding planes and living in sterile rooms while I wrote about people in love. Maybe I could hold the reality at bay with my pointed words.A knock jarred me out of my mind and back into that too white room. A turn of the doorknob, a peek around the door, a breath of relief that it’s just him. No bottle. No sheepish grin, no shrug at the late hour. Just the sunlight on his hair and a genuine look of worry over his face. Come in, how was your last day, are you packed, are you ready, what will you do next, can you believe this view?Until I let one drop of the despair escape. Just one drop of overwhelm running over a cheek and he’s there. Arms wrapped around the black bruise in the too white room. There in solid form with a whisper of comfort and a hint of darkness hidden well beneath his holy sweater. A smell like old paper and ink and the coffee he must have just finished before he knocked on my door. A smell like ancient places I dreamed I had once walked in other lives I couldn’t confirm. I couldn’t let go. Even as he whispered that it was ok and that he wasn’t going anywhere, I couldn’t let go. Even as he promised we would stay in touch, as he promised those late nights hadn’t just been about loneliness. Even as heechoed my fear of what came next, I couldn’t let go of the place I had arrived after so many miles. He stood steady, arms only holding tighter, sweater only getting wetter, the white room only growing darker as the sun dipped behind the city.What’s next?Whatever we want. Wherever we want. Look at me.I can’t. I can’t let you see me.I see you. I have seen you for months. I see you. Look at me.{ Slowly, eyes meeting eyes. }I see you and I only want to come closer. I only want to sleep in your night.
I only want you to stay in my reach.
I only want to love you.Can you?I already do.And there in his grey eyes was a hint of moonlight meeting my night. There in his lips was the promise of just a hint of light to guide me. There in his touch was the healing of the bruises. The city rose up to meet us as we sank into the too white bed, two ink stains on fresh paper.November 27, 2022“20230818_ink_stains.jpg” could not be found.]]></description><link>03-flowers/short-stories/2022-11-27-ink-stains.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/short stories/2022 11 27 Ink Stains.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 15:08:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024 02 02 Bindings]]></title><description><![CDATA[I'm still tied in your old knots.
All of you. All of your ties.
Soft velvet cracked old leather. { they chafe just the same }Ghost bindings made of words
and indifference. Young mouths
with mature plans young hands
building sandcastles in folded time.I am bound to old concrete
shadows of form, drained by ghost
teeth and old mouths
dripping red promises.Always sweet tongued
until the bleeding starts.February 2, 2024<img alt="Bindings-2.png" src="media/writing/bindings-2.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2024-02-02-bindings.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2024 02 02 Bindings.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:55:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="media/writing/bindings-2.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="media/writing/bindings-2.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024 02 You Are Not the Sunrise]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are not the sunrise.
You are the remains
of last nights rain on asphalt.As much at fault as pitter patter
raindrops dropping skitter skatter
apologies from your dry tongue.Old weather glints in the sun
and we ask whether what was lost
is worth the cost of holding on
until another lightning round.But then we are not the sunrise.
We are eyes closed to fate, predictors
of the coming hate sewing
a blanket of night. Sowing chance
in the space between holding tight
and the frozen distance of overdue
escape. I mistook you for the dawn,
but you were the light of a dying star.You are not the sunrise,
but a grey morning storm warning
of old scars and fraying skies.“You-Are-Not-the-Sunrise.png” could not be found.]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2024-02-you-are-not-the-sunrise.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2024 02 You Are Not the Sunrise.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:14:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 04 05 Insubstantial]]></title><description><![CDATA[We are insubstantial
like the legs of waterbirds
holding the weight
of our own hollow bones
and micro-plastic blood.on the edge of flighton the edge of extinctionBelieving in our solidity,
existing as a reflection
in a ripple of cold water.April 5, 2023“insubstantial.jpg” could not be found.]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2023-04-05-insubstantial.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2023 04 05 Insubstantial.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:01:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 03 27 Green]]></title><description><![CDATA[You don’t remember
what green means,
fresh and bursting
from snow fed mud.
What first blades
can teach you
after many months
of monochrome grey.You have become unyielding
like dry husks
of milkweed, shedding
silver strands of fall
while you lie dormant
dreaming of monarchs.For you I will paint
nothing but flowers
until color returns
to your face and you
remember how to open
to the sun before
true birth of leaves.I will paint you nothing but flowers
until you remember how to bloom.March 27, 2023“green_photo.jpg” could not be found.]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2023-03-27-green.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2023 03 27 Green.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:00:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 08 07 Penance for the Pain]]></title><description><![CDATA[Penance for the PainThe mirror was an old one, blackened with time, but Lucas could still make out his face in the dim light of the bedroom. He was hideous. His hair had thinned to streaks of an ink pen on a white canvas. A scar of waxy skin covered his right cheek. The red of his eyes was only made worse by the empty bottle at his feet. He carried a constant pain in his right cheek from a rotten molar and he cherished the pain as penance for his sins. He held it tight like a mouthful of Hail Marys, each throb another bead on a black rosary. He flipped up the hood of his sweatshirt and turned away from his reflection, relief flooding through him that this time the mirror hadn’t turned into a windshield flying toward his face, and that he wouldn’t have to look again until tomorrow morning when he’d dress to face another day that didn’t want him in it. Everyday since the accident had been a day that didn’t want him here. He was supposed to have died with them that night, but here he was, preparing for another visit to a couch, a bright room that saw his every flaw, and a man who never listened when Lucas asked him not to look so closely.He walked to the kitchen where he could still smell the memory of steak and Elena’s body wash. He shook out the pills the doctor had prescribed and washed them down with yesterday’s cold coffee. He felt their movement all the way down his throat as if they too wanted to seal off his share of air. He shut his eyes and for an instant the kitchen seemed to melt around him, replaced with a wet street soaking into his pant legs, blood pouring over his hands, and the smell of gas registering like an alarm in his amygdala telling him to flee. His breath quickened and his eyes shot open, searching for five things in the room he could see, hear, and touch, just as the doctor had instructed. When his breath slowed, Lucas grabbed his backpack and set out through his old neighborhood.The potted flowers on the steps of his townhouse were long dead, the chipped paint on the white railing revealed a patina of old metal beneath. As Lucas started down the steps, he shrunk back in horror as the railing turned to bone, the paint into burnt flesh peeling back from muscle and vein. He squeezed his eyes shut as he had learned to do over the past few months. Wait it out. It was just a memory. It was just his damn, messed up memory. He hurried past the melting arm and continued toward the psychiatrist’s office. He could no longer drive or ride in anything with an engine. He no longer trusted anything but his tennis shoes on familiar sidewalks.&nbsp;At the corner shop, Mr. Peterson was putting up a sign advertising a sale on fresh cut steaks. Mr. Peterson’s shop was a staple of the neighborhood run by a gentle, welcoming man who chuckled at local gossip and suddenly remembered something was on sale when a customer didn’t have enough money. Over the years Lucas went from buying candy bars on his way home from school, to stopping in on Friday evenings to buy flowers and cheap wine to take home to Elena. He always remembered to ask Mr. Peterson about his son who was studying at M.I.T. Lucas had heard the pride in Mr. Peterson’s voice and he had hoped he too would one day speak of his own child like that. But his child never became more than blood on a street corner from a dead womb.Mr. Peterson looked up from his sign and gave Lucas a sad smile, “Lucas, it’s been so long. How are you, son? Would you like to come in?”Lucas caught a glimpse of himself in the reflection of the shop window, black holes where his eyes once looked to the future and a twisted mouth that had once made vows of forever rippled in the glass. Lucas didn’t know how Mr. Peterson could stand to look at him with his scars and his shame and his loss dripping like rain water from his skin.“No thank you, Mr. Peterson. I’m sorry. I have somewhere to be,” Lucas mumbled without looking up from the sidewalk. He wouldn’t drag Mr. Peterson into a life of pills, shrinks, and visions of mirrors that shattered over him like shards of windshield glass.This is why he kept his eyes staring forward at the changing stoplights. There were too many people who wanted to see him smile with perfect white teeth and to admit that he was the one who should have had a steering wheel embedded in his chest, since he was the reason Elena had been driving that night when the rain had turned to sleet, and the black road had turned to black ice. Because he had too much to drink. Because he had argued with her over the baby. Only a few more blocks. Only a few more haunted landmarks. He could see the windows in his peripheral vision, bulging outwards to look more closely at his sins. No longer a child on a bicycle in a long stretch of summer, but a monster hiding from the burning of autumn.Slowly the quiet neighborhood melted into a busy business district and Lucas tried to melt into the crowd of people with lives that hadn’t crashed and burned on a January street. When he arrived at the psychiatrist’s office, he stopped underneath the reddening maple to ready himself for what came next. As he watched, the shadows of the leaves became tiny lost souls crawling over the sidewalk. He could almost hear them calling out to him to save them. He closed his eyes at the thought of the soul of his unborn child drifting somewhere, alone, maybe afraid, and he wanted to scoop these tiny shadows into his pocket and take them home. Instead he convinced himself to look away and entered the building for another round of lies. Always “it’s not your fault” and “you can’t blame yourself.” Fuck if he couldn’t. He’d been doing a pretty damn good job of it for months now.Dr. McClellan’s office was blessedly dimly lit. He had no receptionist and the office was always empty at the time of his regular Friday afternoon appointment. He counted the squares on the beige rug while he waited with the magazines on mindfulness, the sign reading, “Please Silence Your Phone,” and the wall clock whose hands never moved. It was always 11:17 on Friday at Dr. McClellan’s office.Within minutes, Dr. McClellan, in his brown blazer and white beard, opened the door to his inner office. He waved Lucas in and settled himself in his leather arm chair, moleskin notebook on his knee, fountain pen in his hand, wireframes perched on the bridge of his nose. Lucas again felt the feeling of time standing still. He sat on the couch opposite the doctor and pulled off the hood of his sweatshirt. He adjusted his sparse hair as he sighed and steeled himself for what he knew was coming.“How have you been feeling, Lucas?” asked Dr. McClellan in his Freudian voice, an accent Lucas couldn’t quite place.“Like my brain is fucking with me. Like nothing is solid. Like everything is just waiting to melt.”“Have you been drinking?”“Yes.”“Too much?”There was no use lying. “Yes.”The doctor only nodded in reply. “Have you been taking your medication?”“Yes. I took some before I left the house.”“Good,” the doctor nodded. “It will help. Do you want to get started where we left off last week? With that night?”Lucas clenched his eyes shut, every cell of his body screaming at him to just get up and leave and not ever tell anyone about that night. Sell the townhouse, move away. Die a slow death alone and rot into the soil, if the ground would have him. Somewhere from outside the office he heard a ticking, like a clock, but the clock was broken he reminded himself. He felt his limbs grow heavy, his thoughts quiet until all of the self hatred was gathered in a pinprick in the center of his forehead. He began to unwind the clock.“I got off early that day. It was a Friday. I stopped at Peterson’s and bought a bottle of champagne for me and a sparkling cider for Elena. A dozen roses. Two fresh steaks. I told Mr. Peterson that we were going to celebrate. I got a raise, we were having a baby. Everything was going to get better. Mr. Peterson was so happy for us. I was so happy for us.”Lucas’s voice seemed to give out. He didn’t think he could continue. The ticking grew louder for a moment, his mind shrank again to a pinprick, and the doctor said in his soothing, unknown voice, “It’s ok, Lucas. You are safe. Thoughts, memories, they can’t hurt you anymore. Just go on.”“Elena was home when I walked in the door, sitting at the kitchen table with a notepad in front of her, writing quickly. When she saw me come in, she turned the pad over and said she wasn’t expecting me so early. I said I wanted to celebrate the baby, and the fact I got a raise. She didn’t seem excited about the raise which seemed strange since we were barely getting by with just the two of us. We needed the money for the baby. I said that. The money will help with the baby. The baby.”Lucas stopped again. A tear slid over the scar of his cheek. He barely felt it. He only felt a slight nudge of his mind from the hand of the doctor, yet no words were spoken.“Elena said I didn’t need to worry about the baby. I didn’t even need to worry about her. She said that she had done something stupid. She had been writing me a letter to tell me. She pushed the notebook to me and I read what she couldn’t say. She wasn’t sure the baby was mine. She was sorry. It wasn’t supposed to have meant anything. I wasn’t supposed to have known. I didn’t know what to say. We had a few problems, sure, but she had seemed happy. We had seemed happy. She sat looking at me with such sad eyes. Such beautiful, sad eyes. I left the house. I walked for an hour. I stopped in the neighborhood pub. I drank too much. In the haze I realized I didn’t care. So what? So what if the baby wasn’t mine? We could still make it work.”Another pause, another nudge, another feeling like he was suspended between ticks of an unseen clock.“I left the pub to walk home. It was just turning from a cold rain to a sleet. As I was waiting to cross the street, I saw a familiar car pass in front of me. Elena was driving our car and she turned her head and saw me. Those sad eyes. They held mine and in that moment I thought everything was going to be ok. We were going to work it all out. Our whole future felt like it was hanging in that moment.”“Did she stop the car? Did she pick you up to take you home?”“No. I… I looked away and saw that the stoplight had turned red while she had been looking at me. I started to wave at her to stop. She looked ahead and slammed on the breaks, but it was too late. The road had turned icy. And… and she slid headfirst into a truck that was turning left in front of her. The sound. Oh, God, Dr. McClellan! The sound! I don’t want to hear the sound!”Lucas could hear the gnashing of metal against metal. He could feel the teeth of the truck biting into the hood of their car. He was there on the sidewalk while Elena was smashing into the steering wheel and ice was falling in his eyes and he was running, running toward her to save what was left.“Lucas. Focus. Look at me. You are at my office. We are just talking. I want you to look at my face, Lucas.”Lucas concentrated on slowing his breath. He looked at the doctor’s face and tried to place where he had seen the man before. Not here in the office, but somewhere. He nodded that he was ready to continue.“I ran up to the car and tried to open the door, but it wouldn’t open. The man in the truck was bleeding, but ok. He got out and tried to help me open the door. We finally managed to get it open and Elena… Elena was, hardly Elena. The airbag hadn’t gone off. She was…”“It’s ok, Lucas. You don’t have to tell me those details now. You don’t have to look so closely at her right now. Let’s just move on to what happened next.”Tears streamed down Lucas’s face and mixed with the freezing rain on a couch on a street in a winter in an autumn, and he decided not to look away.“The man in the truck and I pulled her out of the car. There was so much blood. It was everywhere. The man said we needed to move away from the crash because he could see gas leaking and it might be dangerous. We lifted Elena from the street and I could hear sirens in the distance. We laid her down on the sidewalk. Her chest, her chest… nothing but blood. As the paramedics arrived, the fire started. It was so hot even from that distance. I felt like I was melting&nbsp; in spite of the sleet. The paramedics took Elena and I climbed in the back of the ambulance. The firetruck was just pulling in as we pulled out. Sirens screaming. Maybe I was screaming. The paramedics tried. They did! They tried! But there was no Elena left. There was only her blood mixed with our baby on the sheets. They told me she was dead at the hospital. I looked at my watch. 11:17. 11:17 on a Friday night. Because of me.”“Lucas, why do you think it’s because of you? What did you do?”“I left. I got drunk. I should have stayed and talked it out. She wouldn’t have been driving on the icy streets to look for me if I had been a fucking man and stayed and worked it out with her!”The doctor handed Lucas a familiar piece of notebook paper. “Or not. Read this, Lucas.”Lucas unfolded the paper and saw Elena’s slanted handwriting. It was the letter she had been writing, only she had added to it after he left for the pub. Lucas read that while Elena had thought the other man didn’t matter to her, he had. That she was leaving Lucas to be with him. That she was sorry. He refolded the paper and looked at the doctor, who looked much less like Sigmund Freud than he had when Lucas came in.“She was leaving me? She wasn’t coming to pick me up that night? She was leaving to be with him? I don’t understand. That’s not what I remember at all.”“Do you remember when you first came to see me you described what had happened? That you had gotten drunk and Elena came to get you at the bar? She had been angry with you for drinking when she needed you at home. How you had caused the accident? All I saw was a young man with PTSD and a head full of false memories. When the standard therapy wasn’t working, I thought you would be a good candidate for a new trial therapy. We haven’t been giving you Xanax. We have been microdosing you with a mild hallucinogenic which has proven very effective in the treatment of PTSD.”“But you told me I was taking Xanax. You lied to me! Isn’t that against some kind of Hippocratic oath?”
“Do you remember that you agreed to be a part of a PTSD study? You agreed to undergo experimental treatment. I have your signature here.”“I don’t know. I don’t remember. I don’t know. I… I… She was leaving me. It wasn’t my baby. I wasn’t with her in the car when it happened. But I remember it so clearly! I have this scar.” Lucas ran his hands over his face, feeling only smooth skin, ran his hands through his thick, unkempt hair. “I really don’t know what’s happening. The pills! Is that why I’ve been seeing such weird shit?”“PTSD has been known to cause false memories. The hallucinations were an unexpected side effect of the medication that I hoped would resolve itself before now, especially the view you had of yourself. It seems you somehow developed an outer perception of yourself that you felt matched the inner you. Very interesting, actually.”Lucas grabbed his hair in his hands and looked again at the beige carpet where Elena now lay as if asleep. He began to wail like that January night as he slid from the couch to the floor and cradled her in his arms.“I’m sorry, Elena. I’m sorry I couldn’t save you. I’m sorry I couldn’t let you go before now.” He saw every detail of her flawless skin before her image dissolved and he was left kneeling in an ordinary office on an everyday Friday. The doctor reached out a hand and placed it on Lucas’s shoulder.“Now we begin the work of healing.”The doctor was just an average man, the room an average room, the silence not as deep, the ticking just a regular wall clock. Lucas nodded and sat back on the couch.“I can’t say that I understand anything that’s happened. I can’t say today what’s even real. It wasn’t my fault, but Elena deserved so much better. It all feels unresolved. It all feels wrong. Can you help me make sense of it?”“I will certainly try, Lucas.”As he left the office and walked home down the same uneven sidewalks, Lucas still wasn’t sure that the shadows weren’t trying to pull him under, but he felt the clock begin to move forward again. It was Friday at noon, the beginning of fall. He stopped in front of Mr Petersons’s shop, and caught his reflection in the window. Just a broken man with shaggy brown hair, teeth that needed brushing, and a body that could use a good meal. Lucas hesitated, pushed open the door, heard the familiar jingle of the bell, and stepped inside.August 7, 2023<a href=".?query=tag:shortstory" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#shortstory">#shortstory</a> Feedback:from professor: There were so many standout lines throughout this short story that wowed me. Your talent for crafting a memorable sentence is incredible. When it comes to feedback for this piece, I think expanding this story could help prepare the reader for the twist and give more time for the resolution. I'd add a few more foreshadowing details and give more time to digest the twist. Excellent work! 94%]]></description><link>03-flowers/short-stories/2023-08-07-penance-for-the-pain.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/short stories/2023 08 07 Penance for the Pain.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 02:59:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 07 08 Bottled Up Wishes]]></title><description><![CDATA[We once drank starlight from fluted champaign glasses, on a balcony overlooking the lives of ten million people. We poured love into each other’s ears and let the sheets pool onto the floor as the streetlights threw shadows over bare skin. We drank black coffee at midnight and ate toast over the Sunday crossword, laughing when we could only fill in a third of the squares. I wrote poetry on his palm in purple ink so he could put me in his pocket when his hands got cold on the corner waiting for the bus. He felt like forever until the morning I clearly heard him say, “I wish you would just shut the fuck up so I can tell you goodbye.”“What did you say?” I asked, shocked because just last night he had told me how you loved the way I could tell a story.“I didn’t say anything, but I do need to get going to the bus stop.”“Elliot, you just told me to shut the fuck up. I heard you.”Elliot turned an early sunset shade of pink and stammered, “I, I, I don’t think I did. I do have to get to the bus though.”It wasn’t long before I was sleeping alone on perfectly placed sheets and throwing the crossword in the recycling bin untried. Elliot had told me goodbye a few days later. The forever kind, not the off to the bus stop kind. I suppose I should have told him at some point over the eight months we were together that I can hear other people’s wishes, but it just hadn’t come up. I had honestly thought he might be the only man in the city who never wished for anything. It had been such a relief just to sit with him and not hear a constant stream of things he could never have - a better job, a woman with bigger boobs, a catamaran in the Bahamas. It hurt like hell when the first thing he wished for was for me to shut up.I gave myself a week to stream whole seasons of heartbreak and to sleep wrapped in the dress shirts he had left behind, inhaling what I knew was detergent but pretending it was him. I knew I was healing when I picked up a romance novel and lost myself in the steam. I went back to work the next day and only cried a little when I heard the girl at the next desk say, “I wish my husband would stop wanting to cuddle all the time. I just need some space.”Oh the wishes of the married and secure who didn’t remember what it was like to reach over in the middle of the night and feel nothing but a cold spot and a sense of something missing. Oh how I wished I could accept that cuddling in her place.As I left work for the day I couldn’t resist stopping at her desk and saying, “Enjoy it while you have it, sister. It could all be gone tomorrow.”That might be why everyone at my company avoided me at the Christmas party and the annual picnic, but since I was the only one who knew how to fix our archaic computer system, they had to at least pretend to be nice to me at work.I sometimes wish I could bottle all of these wishes and put them on a shelf in my apartment. Admire the different colors and smells of each one. Watch them swirl behind the glass and know that almost none of them will ever come true. I would especially like to capture the wishes of unrequited love. They are so loud and desperate and there are so, so many of them falling from the rooftops of skyscrapers, that I would like to quiet them with a stopper and never let them out into the world again. There are so few unique wishes. It’s almost always for love or to save a dying family member, which is really the same thing in the end. Yet they are all so earnest in their vibrations, they all are so badly desired that I once tried to make one come true, just to see what would happen.I was on the corner of 54th and Franklin on a hell of a summer day, checking my phone for messages from Elliot when I heard it as if it had circled directly into my cochlea. “I wish I had the nerve to tell him that I want to be more than friends.”I looked to my left and saw a young girl in a pretty strawberry dress gazing adoringly at the small, somewhat nerdy boy next to her. The wish weighed so much that I instinctively felt the need to set it down. I walked over to the pair and announced to the young man that the girl would really like to be more than friends. The girl’s eyes widened in horror and her mouth fell open and flapped around like a plastic bag caught in a tree in January.The boy only kept pushing buttons on the game he was playing and said, “Yeah, I know. But I just want things to stay the way they are.”The girl had run off in tears and I had vowed to never get involved with the business of fulfilling wishes again. Well, if you don’t count Elliot and the fact that I did shut the fuck up and allow him to say goodbye. Sometimes it happens accidentally, but it’s not like I have much control over that. I’ve also learned that much like my coworker who would probably feel neglected if her husband actually stopped wanting to cuddle, most people don’t actually want their wishes fulfilled and they feel a sense of guilt when they do get what they want. Well, again, except Elliot who hasn’t bothered to text me or even ask for his dress shirts back, which is a good thing since I took them to Goodwill with a wish that they would find a good home.I was tired of my silent apartment and drinking wine by myself on a balcony meant for two, so I did something I never do - I went to a bar. I avoid bars because the wishes of drunks are&nbsp; generally sex or sports related. Although there is often the one really sad drunk who either wishes his wife hadn’t left him or that he was a better dad to his grown kids. It breaks my heart either way that life only moves in one direction and we can’t undo all the stupid decisions our younger selves made for us.The bar wasn’t too crowded on this Wednesday night and the normal sound of the basketball game on the giant screen TV had been replaced by Lizzo reminding me that I’m a bad bitch who doesn’t need a man. I slid onto a stool and remembered how Lizzo had been Elliot’s favorite for about two months the summer before. I ordered a drink and slid into a memory of how it felt to drink with someone else when you knew that later the empty glasses will sit together on the nightstand while the alcohol lets you whisper your wishes into the hollow of your lover’s collarbone. How I wished that I could channel my inner Lizzo, forget about Elliot, and just take someone home and let the liquor do it’s thing.“I’m sorry you were hurt,” said a voice two stools down.“I’m sorry, what?” I asked.“Elliot. I’m sorry he left you.”I stared at the man with the kind eyes while the night stretched like old leather and I knew then how naked the girl in the strawberry dress had felt when I had exposed her.“I didn’t mention anything about any Elliot.”
“Oh, really? I’m sorry. I must have the wrong person. It must have been someone else in here on the phone. I’m so sorry. Just ignore me. Too many drinks in already,” the man said with a gentle smile and a tilt of his lowball.Could it be true? Could there be another person like me? It couldn’t be a coincidence. It just couldn’t be. So I tried again.“I wish that someone else could hear the wishes that fill the air like gnats on a summer night,” I whispered in my head.I looked at the man. He looked up at me with a slow look of surprise and I caught the slight slur in his silent reply, “I wish that someone would take this weight off of my lungs because they can’t handle even one more day breathing in wishes in this city of so many lonely people.”I slid off my stool and sat down next to him.“I’m Mia,” I said, “and I would love to carry some of that weight so that you can breathe a little easier.”“I’m Arman and while I don’t know you that well yet, I think that Elliot must have been a damned fool.”Just then the door banged open and a young woman huffed into the bar, sat down heavily in a booth, and I knew that we both heard just what kind of a day she had just had.“I wish he would get hit by the 8:00 bus! I wish he would fall off the edge of earth and asphyxiate in space! I wish he would be clawed to death by a million tiny crawfish!”“Here’s to heartbreak, Arman,” I said with a tilt of my Malbec.He clinked his glass to mine, “And to the gift of unfulfilled wishes.”July 8, 2023<a href=".?query=tag:shortstory" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#shortstory">#shortstory</a>from professor: Amazing story! I had a smile on my face throughout so much of this story. The descriptions and details were so creatively written. The plot was well executed and kept the reader interested. Fantastic work! 90%<br><img alt="Bottled Up Wishes.png" src="media/writing/bottled-up-wishes.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>03-flowers/short-stories/2023-07-08-bottled-up-wishes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/short stories/2023 07 08 Bottled Up Wishes.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 02:58:42 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2023 07 02 Denial]]></title><description><![CDATA[DenialLogan had just gotten a haircut that morning. He’d called his friend Aisha and made plans to meet her for lunch next week. He’d bought his dog a new leash and collar and told Aisha he was going to take the dog for more walks to get them both in better shape. Three days later he washed up on the shore of Lake Michigan with no signs of foul play, his death eventually ruled accidental. He’d been drunk, maybe he fell in, it happened all the time. Aisha kept his dog, attended his memorial, and wept with his family at the seemingly pointless way of things, and life in the city went on. Only the man who read about it in on the Chicago Tribune website a week later knew the truth, scowling as he put his keys in his pocket and went out for another night on the town.As he passed bar after bar, the streetlights making the night feel like day, he puzzled over whether or not he could count this “Logan” as the first. It felt a bit hollow, a bit unfinished. It certainly hadn’t felt like he was sure the first one would have felt. He had envisioned everything about the night, right down to the Nirvana t-shirt he had worn, the one with the smiley face, but that was the only thing that had gone as planned. He was supposed to have persuaded the guy to get in his car, taken him to Osterman Beach and filleted him like a fresh caught trout before he dumped him into Lake Michigan as fish food, but this “Logan” had ruined the whole thing with his $200 haircut and his problems and his secrets. This “Logan” who had denied him his relief.He pulled his freshly detailed car up to the curb outside of The Green Mill, tried to calm his racing heart, and let his eyes scan the crowd for the loner, the person no one would miss right away. The man with just the right amount of stumble to his gait that signaled he had drank more than he planned and now needed a ride home to sleep it off. This is where it had all gone wrong with that “Logan.” He should have sensed the air of hopelessness about his prey, but instead he had rolled down his window, offered the man in the clean khakis a ride, “You’ll wait awhile for an Uber, dude, might as well hop in and I’ll drive you for less,” he had told Logan. And Logan had taken the bait. He’d collapsed into the back seat, but then instead of an address, he’d asked to be taken to The Belmont Rocks.“What do you want to go there for at this time of night? Come on, man, let me take you home,” he had kindly told Logan. “No charge. You just seem like you could use a good night’s rest.”“I could use a lot of things, but advice from a guy making his living driving a knock-off Uber isn’t one of them. I want to go to the rocks. I want to see the water. I want to remember.”So he’d driven him to the lake shore. It was the plan anyway, right? So what if the guy was going there willingly instead of demanding to know where he was being taken? He was still in control. He was still the only one who knew the ending, so he’d taken Logan to the rocks. He’d followed him as he’d gotten out of the car and weaved his way to the limestone wall that lined the lake shore. He’d watched as Logan watched the water, pulled at his hair, and cried out in an agony that came from some ancient place in his DNA, and he’d felt compelled to know where this grief originated. He wanted to know if he’d be doing his victim a favor rather than robbing him of something precious.“Hey, man, do you want to talk about it? Come away from the rocks, I’m afraid you’ll fall in. Maybe it would help to talk to someone, especially a stranger, you know? Leave it with someone who doesn’t even know ya. Then I’ll take you home. Just step back and let’s talk.”Logan had backed up a few feet, run his fingers through that too perfect hair again, and had said in almost a whisper, “It’s all a lie. It’s all been a lie.”The city lights stood at a distance as if waiting to be invited to the conversation, the moon&nbsp; hung low and tried to pull at the lake that refused to be guided by gravity, a star or two did its best to compete against the ingenuity of man, and the driver felt his fingers twitch at the thought of the knife in his pocket. He prompted his prey, “What’s a lie?”“All of it!” Logan yelled as the water hit the rocks with a surprising force. “My whole life! These pressed clothes, my high-rise condo! The whole fucking thing! This place! This place is the only truth. The only place where I can feel free.”“The rocks? Why here, man? What’s here for you but crumbling limestone and pollution?”“They used to come here when they had no where else to go. People like me. They came here because it’s where they could be a part of something. I don’t know that I’m a part of anything! No one knows who I am! It’s supposed to be ok now, you know? It’s supposed to be accepted! But here I am with a job and a dog and friends, and the risk of losing everything if I tell anyone. I’d rather sacrifice myself to the ghosts than keep on this way!”“Ah, I see. In the closet, huh? Why? No one cares anymore, right? They even have that rainbow shit at Target now. They have that show with the five dudes who make people pretty. It’s all good, my man.” Why was he trying to talk this guy down? Why did he genuinely want him to feel ok with who he was? He came here to cut him open and count the rings of his life, not to teach him self love, but he knew what it was to live with secrets and he knew what it took to quiet them and keep them hidden. Mostly he wanted the guy to not want to die so the killing would satisfy the need to take something someone dearly wanted to keep.“You don’t understand. No one understands! I tried! I tried to tell Aisha. I tried to tell my mom, but they both brushed it away. They told me I just needed to meet the right girl. There was a partner at my firm who came out two months ago. They finally found a reason to let him go last week. It’s not as easy as you think! It’s not easy at all.”With that Logan slumped to the ground. His shoulders heaved as the lake soaked into his creases and the breeze ruffled his hair. “The people who came here were braver than I can ever be. Too many of them paid the ultimate price.”
“So this is how you honor them? By giving up? By throwing yourself into a watery grave? This is how you remember the ones who gave everything and were left to waste away? This is how you honor your past? Man, I think maybe you’re better than that. I think you came here to let the ghosts guide you. Not to join them, but to be joined to them. But what do I know? I’m just a knock-off Uber driver in a vintage Nirvana shirt.”Logan gave a shadow of a smile, “Vintage? I saw that same shirt at Target last week, right next to the rainbow shit, as you call it.”Logan walked onto the rocks and stared out at the darkness waiting to swallow him whole. He exhaled the last of the whiskey he’d drank an hour earlier, and said, “You know, I flirted with a very nice man tonight. I just bought my dog a new leash.” He was silent for a few crashes of the tide.“Maybe you’re right. Maybe it was fate that put me in your car tonight. Maybe… maybe I can find a way to stop pretending. If not, I guess this place will still be here next week. Take me home. Please.” He turned to face the driver only to be met with moonlight reflecting off a blade just inches from his face.“What the… Why??”“I’m sorry, man, really. It’s not you. In fact, I thought about just taking you home, but it has to be tonight, see? It was supposed to be tonight. But, this has nothing to do with who you are, really. I’m a lotta things, but I’m not a bigot. It just had to be tonight. It has to be now. I’ve waited too long. I’m really sorry.”“Then why didn’t you just let me kill myself? Why talk me out of it?”“It has to be me who decides! It has to be me who does the killing!”The driver slammed his hand against the steering wheel as he continued to scan the crowd outside of The Green Mile. He came back here because it was where it had all gone wrong last time. This is where he needed to be to make it right. All because of Mr. Perfect. All because that “Logan’s” foot had slipped on the damn wet limestone right before the knife had found his flesh and he fell as if in slow motion into the waves of Lake Michigan. He’d screamed for help. He’d flailed and fought the tide, but eventually it won. The driver had just stood there, watching. Hadn’t reached out a hand, hadn’t called for help, hadn’t grabbed his cell and dialed 911. Just watched as the body of his first victim was battered against the rocks, his $200 haircut turning into pulp, and puzzled over whether or not it counted. Were you a killer if all you did was let a person die? That was still what bothered him as he sat watching the last of the patrons stream out of the bar. Would this be number one or number two? He brushed a piece of lint from his new t-shirt, scanned the crowd, and vowed that this time he wouldn’t let some sad sack control the evening. This time he would be the one to do the talking and the taking. This time he would be the one to decide who lives or dies.He rolled down his window, “You’ll wait awhile for an Uber, dude, might as well hop in and I’ll drive you for less,” he said to the man with less than perfect hair. And to his delight, the man crawled in, gave him an address, laid his head back, and closed his eyes. The driver put the car in gear, smiled, and drove east with his offering to the lake.*Written for Creative Writing summer 2023, Professor Brunig100%Wow! What a spectacular story. I was hooked from the first line and found myself flying through to discover what was next. You did such a fantastic job constantly surprising the reader. With each reveal, we had new questions, so the tension never lessened until the very end. My only feedback is wondering why the narrator wasn't more nervous/excited/etc. if Logan was supposed to be his first. I live by The Green Mill, so that was a fun detail to read! Since I know it, I'd also suggest adding detail about their iconic neon green sign. Otherwise, fantastic job.Submitted to Spire magazine, December 2023
published in Spire Magazine 2024]]></description><link>03-flowers/short-stories/2023-07-02-denial.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/short stories/2023 07 02 Denial.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 02:57:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2022 11 29 We Are Made of Endings]]></title><description><![CDATA[I dreamt of endings. Frayed strands of yarn, a dead end road, storm clouds rolling out and giving way to blue, the check arriving on a scarred table in a pub at the end of the world. Every night the dreams began at the end and only faded to black like the last scene of an old film. I spent my daylight hours trying to recreate the scene that had come before, but there was nothing. No hint of a remembered dream pulling at the edges of my mind. Just the ending.Then one morning there was only the last bite of a muffin left in the box. The next day only the last sip of cold coffee left in the cup freshly poured. The following afternoon there was only the wrap up of a meeting. The next evening only the last mile to drive home. I spent my nighttime hours trying to recreate the scenes that must have come before, but there was nothing. No hint of a remembered life pulling at the edges of my mind. Only endings.A visit to my doctor, a referral to a neurologist, the last few minutes of a consultation, the table leaving the MRI scanner with no memory of going in. The assurance that everything was fine as the doctor left the room. Getting up from a chair in the psychiatrist’s office with an appointment for another session next week, maybe you have some unremembered trauma, we’ll discuss it more next time. this session was very enlightening. I was only left more in the dark. What had I said? What had I told this stern looking woman with the wire frames and fountain pen? I couldn’t remember walking in the office let alone the words that had left my mouth. Only the ending.Weeks continued on the same way. Dreams of last breaths, falling leaves, the sputtering of a wick in a pool of wax, orgasm without touch, so many backs as people walked away. Days spent consuming last gulps of coffee, last bites of food, the last chapter of every novel. Meetings wrapping up, arriving home without the drive, stepping out of the shower dripping wet without stepping in, hanging up the phone without remembering who I had been talking to. Back to the neurologist, “are you sure? are you sure there isn’t something there? look again.” Back to the psychiatrist, “it’s all slipping away. make it stay. make me more than a last moment. i am only an ending.”Finally opening my eyes to a sterile room in a white gown with tiny faded green dots, just as the light from the setting sun was hitting the dresser on the far side of the room, illuminating the vase of wilting flowers and a water glass with one final sip. I didn’t rise. I didn’t question how this had all happened. It was just another ending.I had often missed the first buds in the spring, a storm rolling in on a sunny day, my heart skipping a beat when I opened the door for a first date. I hadn’t savored being handed the menu to choose, reaching out to take a cup of coffee, fresh and steaming, lighting an unburned wick, turning to the title page of an unread book, letting my hands wander over a body I knew would soon be wrapped around my own. I had seldom thought, “this is the beginning. this moment is where it all starts.” I was made of forgotten beginnings.But the endings, when I was satiated, sad, shattered, thrilled, lost, content… alone, then I knew. Then I stopped to remember that there was a beginning to this ending. There was a spot where I decided I was all in, without the realization that life is just endings, as spring is just the end of winter. As I lay in the ultimate end, alone without even the memory of arriving in this place, I could only feel joy for the reminder that my life had been full of beginnings I never took the time to see. That the way the light was fading in the room was really just the start of the last night. Only the beginning.The beginning of the last night when it all became clear. When I walked out of the sterile room and saw every person who passed me as the joining of ovum and sperm, spinning strands of DNA, an atom of carbon. The hallway darkened to a single point of light in the distance of a cavernous emptiness. The faded dots of my gown floated into the darkness like fireflies to guide my body shed of clothing and worries.I followed as I dissolved into cells, into elements, into galaxies. I spun through the darkness with eight billion other swirling clouds of hydrogen and helium, light and heat, heavy with potential. We had been destroyers. We had been the riders of the apocalypse leaving destruction in our wake. The fellers of trees, the bullets through flesh, the plastic suspended in salt water, the cement over bones. We had been eight billion little endings. Eight billion little endings swirling into one cloud, one singular point of light, one spot blinking in a universe of unnamed black. A heavy mass of souls in a tiny singularity. Waiting. Just another beginning.{ Published in the 2023 Edition of the Elgin Community College Spire Literary Magazine}“stardust.jpeg” could not be found.]]></description><link>03-flowers/short-stories/2022-11-29-we-are-made-of-endings.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/short stories/2022 11 29 We Are Made of Endings.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 02:57:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024 08 11 City Lights]]></title><description><![CDATA[over his left shoulder
city lights
on off on
there and gone
rhythmic brilliancea taste of downtown
I want to savor
it all at oncethe whole scene
somewhere
on the other side
of his hair
curled at his neckunder the breath
and sweat I am here
and there and herebeneath a heartbeat
and there
above the skylineAugust 11, 2024]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2024-08-11-city-lights.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2024 08 11 City Lights.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:40:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024 03 30 Marble Gardens (Sestina)]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let's write poetry on our palms in blue ink,
like cheat notes for a midterm on existence.
Let's lie in marble gardens, study the curves
that contour lifetimes. Paint scars and realities
one stroke at a time, naked on stretched canvas,
watercolors bleeding on the very edge of hunger.We'll carry our poems and collaborate our hunger.
Tattoo our desires with each other's ink
on our bodies made to be each other's canvas.
Paint me into your vision of existence.
Compose me from your synonyms for reality.
Sketch in thick charcoal my every curve.I will take you in and fit your words to my curves,
create ballads to the way your insatiable hunger
awaits what falls from my fountain pen of realities.
Together we will create museums of blue ink
and stone to prove the facts of our existence,
like a finger painting of pink petals on old canvas.Pink petals covering the scars of a used canvas,
raining over intertwined fingers, filling the curves
on a path carved by the unlikely existence
of two people in a world of eight billion hungry
mouths desiring to consume marble and ink
as cheat notes guiding them to gatekept realities.Through watercolor soliloquies, we release realities
into a world tired of staring at a blank, white canvas,
trying to make sense of the ever changing ink
blot tests of continuous existential crisis, curve
balls and red tape allowing for rampant hunger.
Let our words of desire create a new existence.Here in this garden, we create an artist's existence
through touch and fingertips exploring realities.
We quench our own thirst and feed a deep hunger
for tomorrows roughly sketched on canvas,
and outlined on the page in cursive curves -
a love story of two, inspiring the world through ink.Let's write realities on our palms in blue ink,
explore a hunger for scars in our curves -
render another existence on stretched canvas.March 30, 2024Other Versions:let's write poetry on
our palms in blue ink
cheat notes for a
midterm on existencelie in marble gardens
study the curves
that contour a lifetimepaint scars and truths
one stroke at a time
until we are naked
on stretched canvas -watercolors blending on
the very edge of hungerApril 6, 2022Let's write poetry on our palms in blue ink,
cheat notes for a midterm on existence.
Let's lie in marble gardens, study the curves
that contour a lifetime, paint scars and truths
on stroke at a time, naked on stretched canvas,
watercolors blending on the edge of hunger.]]></description><link>03-flowers/poetry/2024-03-30-marble-gardens-(sestina).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">03 Flowers/poetry/2024 03 30 Marble Gardens (Sestina).md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 03:39:57 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>